DECEMBER 15, 2021
[♪ pensive music playing]
[indistinct chatter]
[trainer] Good, keep the ball moving!
-[players chatting indistinctly]
[whistle blowing]
[Leonel] It's a gamble.
At that moment, I didn't know
if Sergio would be a great player
[crowd cheering]
[Pep] Sergio is the legend of this club.
The glory belongs to him.
[indistinct chatter]
-[audience cheering]
[Adriana] From one day to the next,
being told you can’t play
devastating.
It’s not my best angle, but, well,
Whichever works best for you, huh?
Huh? Hey!
[photographer speaking indistinctly]
-[whispers] Come here.
[Sergio] I started remembering everything…
[♪ tense music playing]
…from when I was five years old
SERGIO AGÜERO
All I ever did was play ball.
-[whistle blowing]
[commentator 1] Agüero!
[crowd cheering]
[commentator 2 in English] And they've got
[commentator 3 in Spanish]
[commentator 4] Let's see! Kun, Kun, Kun!
[commentator 5] Sergio Agüero!
[commentator 6] Goal!
-[photographer speaking indistinctly]
[crowd applauding]
[♪ pensive music playing]
KUN BY AGÜERO
[♪ somber music playing]
[reporter] The situation
The rain is getting more intense.
There are areas
Alarm is widespread.
[Adriana] The water had risen to five,
So, I didn’t want to leave the house…
but I started having contractions,
"ADRIANA AGÜERO
so I had to go to hospital.
[indistinct chatter]
[Adriana] The doctor said,
Because there was a 50% chance
and… 50% chance of him surviving.
I was hospitalized for a long time
"OUTPATIENT CLINICS
with an IV
I'm not someone who gives up.
I wasn't going to lose the baby.
[baby crying]
[Adriana] Sergio was born healthy.
He was blessed,
[crowd cheering]
[crowd chanting] City! City!
[Sergio] It all happened very quickly.
I was 23 at the time, in the Premier.
The parade, the whole celebration,
how it all went…
I wasn't fully aware
for City, you know?
-[crowd cheering]
ONE YEAR EARLIER
[Daniel] He was a star in La Liga,
where it was uncertain what would happen.
He arrived at a time when Manchester City
DANIEL FRESCÓ
[Sergio] I liked the Premier League.
[indistinct chatter]
[Sergio] Mancini called me, "Hi, Sergio.
Do you want to come to City?"
I said… He said,
a lot of people speak Spanish."
It's different when a coach calls you,
[Sergio] Because when a coach calls you,
it's because the coach
It's not the same as getting a call
[indistinct chatter]
[crowd cheering]
Sergio needed to come to Manchester City
to take Manchester City to another level.
PABLO ZABALETA
Oh, it's so cold!
[Pablo] I always tried to talk
so Sergio's signing could happen.
[Sergio] It was also a challenge
but it was about showing Mancini
And Zabaleta also helped me a lot.
He's Argentine, but he spoke English,
[gasps]
[gasps, in English] Oh, my God,
[Pablo] He doesn't speak English.
[in Spanish] What did she say? A picture?
[Pablo] No, that she loves you.
[Sergio] Well, I listened
[photographer in English] I'll say,
-Okay?
-[photographer] Say "Together."
-Hernán!
"Together" means "as one," right?
-[Hernán in English] "Together"?
[photographer in English] Play faster.
Play faster.
-[photographer] Great.
[in Spanish] When I got to Manchester,
They were kicking the shit
[indistinct chatter]
And Mancini, who was next to me,
he looked at me and said,
So, Kompany kicked at me.
[players cheer]
And the next time I was able to,
He looked at me and didn't say anything.
And that's how I started to earn
[crowd cheering]
[Sergio] On my debut…
I was anxious and nervous
At that moment,
I was the most expensive signing
[commentator in English]
Which he has brought with him…
[crowd cheering]
…from his boyhood.
Touré.
Johnson. Lovely play!
Agüero!
A debut goal.
And they've got yet another hero here…
Manchester City.
Agüero! Oh, he can't stop that!
It gets even better on his debut.
[♪ inspiring music playing]
[Sergio in Spanish]
In the end,
The referee even gave me the ball.
The guys signed it and everything.
And I remember
and wrote, "Not bad."
"Not bad." I mean, what does he want?
[chuckles]
-[birds chirping]
[commentator] In the center,
When I met him, he was five years old.
JOSÉ LUIS "LUIGGI" SERVIÁN
[trainer] Good, keep moving the ball.
-[players chatting indistinctly]
[Luiggi] He had potential.
-[whistle blowing]
[Luiggi] He was born for this.
He ended up being signed by five clubs.
[Sergio] My dad would always show up
He’d stay in the corners
and bore into me with his gaze.
With just that look, he’d signal, like,
If I wasn’t playing well, he’d get upset
[parent] Way to go! Whoo!
[Leonel] All the parents raved about him,
"No. He’s not a prodigy."
But not because he played badly.
I would point out his flaws…
so he could develop and understand that…
"LEONEL DEL CASTILLO
he was always lacking something.
I never told him he was good.
[Sergio] I would be in the car
I couldn’t say a word
He’d always say, "You're not coming back,
I was just a kid and I would cry.
So, all I could think about was…
"I have to win."
[spectator 1] Come on, Dani!
[Lionel] Come on, Sergio!
[spectator 2] Sergio!
[kid shouts]
[spectator 3] Sergio, hit it hard!
He would tell me, "In the first half,
And I had to do it because otherwise,
[indistinct clamor]
[spectator 4] Go, go, Sergio!
He wanted me to score
in the first half
I could leave that team
Over time, I realized
from all those clubs I played for.
In some games, they would give me money,
and I’d say
We really needed it.
We were always short on cash.
-[whistle blowing]
[Sergio] The game ends and…
the coach tells me,
I'm like, "Okay, let's go."
I mean, I thought,
[♪ curious music playing]
[Sergio] He'd drive me to a place
and would say, "Give this to your dad."
I think it was 20 pesos,
And I said…
"Oh." That's when I started thinking,
because, well, with that little bit
we could all eat, you know?
[♪ intriguing music playing]
[Sergio] I would stay overnight
I stayed there on Fridays
and he would take me early.
would take me there too,
because usually
It could have been five or six though.
[♪ intriguing music continues]
[Luiggi] I had a Fiat 600.
I'd load up eight or nine kids,
He practically lived at the field.
[Sergio] They would…
take me home around 10:00 at night.
I'd go straight to bed.
He always told me,
He would take him to play
but as far as I know, it wasn't for money.
Sergio never talked
It was like he put up a shell
[Luiggi] He was chosen.
Uh, I think,
[over recording] That he was going to save
2001 13 YEARS OLD
[whistle blowing]
[Sergio] In a youth soccer match…
we were playing in the finals…
and I remember we were losing.
[whistle blowing]
[Sergio] I was really nervous.
[indistinct chatter]
At one point, I started to feel tired.
Suddenly, my heart started racing.
[heart beating rapidly]
I kind of froze
letting the coach know
He took me to the locker room…
I washed my face…
and it passed, I felt normal again.
If I got nervous about something,
I would calm myself down.
I’d take a deep breath
[whistle blowing]
[Sergio] At Independiente,
it started happening
and I never said anything.
[indistinct chatter]
[birds chirping]
We were about to start ninth grade,
better teams.
[indistinct shouting]
[Sergio] And that’s when I met
The following year,
Now, they're my three best friends.
[player] Thanks, Dami. Have a nice day.
[Pepe] I went to Independiente.
They told me
"JOSÉ "PEPE" SOSA
a kid who played really well.
[whistle blowing]
[Diego] The only thing people talked about
I had gotten into a fight with a teammate.
We were new, I was about to take a shower,
DIEGO CAMPOS
[Diego over recording] So, he told me,
you need to leave." And the first one
That's how it all started.
Normally, those of us from very humble
are often looked at differently
So, when he came in and said
I wanted to defend him to the end.
[Pocho] In the end,
But he was very different
He didn't talk about the games beforehand.
He was very focused, you know?
LUCAS "POCHO" FERNÁNDEZ
But once he stepped onto the field,
[crowd applauding]
2002 14 YEARS OLD
The last match we had to win
I felt like the game was going to be easy.
[spectator] Goal!
[Sergio] We started off winning
[crowd cheering]
Then they evened the score to one-one.
[Diego] We had a disagreement
and we ended up throwing punches.
They sent him off. [chuckles]
Yeah, he always got sent off.
We couldn't score,
-I was getting really desperate…
…and subconsciously I knew
I'd be in for it with my dad, you know?
I made a play down the right,
I was shouting at him to cross it,
He saw me.
-[crowd cheering]
A teammate who wore number seven said…
"Here," and handed me his jersey.
I saw that he was wearing my jersey,
That's when I realized, and I said,
So, I kept playing those last two minutes.
The match ended, and the referee
[chuckles]
-[whistle blowing]
The excitement, just imagine.
No, when we won…
we were super happy.
[chuckles]
[whistle blowing]
THREE YEARS LATER
[Hugo] If I say we chose Agüero
because we knew he would achieve
But we did know
in world soccer, an important player.
HUGO TOCALLI
[♪ curious music playing]
[Sergio] When I was 15,
[Hugo] We noticed that Kun
immediately felt a sense of belonging
He was a very cheerful player,
someone who could make
He was the type of player
During a training camp,
[Sergio] We were having dinner,
I… I didn't know who he was.
[crowd cheering]
[Sergio] The only thing I did
He had some Nikes that I looked at
and thought,
So, I thought,
"Well, he's not from Argentina,
[♪ calm music playing]
I said, "Excuse me, what's your name?"
I asked, "And your last name?" "Messi."
One of the guys told me, "What,
"How can you not know him?
I said, "No, where does he play?"
[over tablet]
and that's how our friendship began.
[Leo] That was the day we met.
LEO MESSI
We were the two youngest in that…
and I was 17. He was 16.
He made everyone laugh at the table
because he wasn't embarrassed by anything
Then I got promoted.
I played a match for the U-20 team,
Miguel Tojo told me,
"I'm going to put you with Messi,
because he said I was going
So, he paired me up with him
so I could start to understand
[♪ tense instrumental music playing]
[crowd cheering]
ONE YEAR EARLIER
[Sergio] In a match…
my heart started racing.
I tried to breathe and calm myself down,
I looked to the bench
because something was happening to me.
[whistle blowing]
It wasn’t 15 or 20 seconds.
It was much longer.
HOME LOCKER ROOM
[Pocho] They were gathered together,
My dad was crying. [chuckles]
I remember they were taking him
[ambulance siren blaring]
[Pocho] Fear and doubt started
What if he couldn't fulfill his dream?
[♪ pensive music playing]
[Roberto] I talked to Sergio, and he said,
"I looked down and saw my jersey moving
ROBERTO PEIDRÓ
[Roberto] He kept asking,
On one hand, if we ended his career,
and maybe it wasn't really necessary
On the other hand,
maybe he had an illness
[machine beeping]
[Sergio] It was tough
I had to stay awake
We did a procedure
where we inserted a catheter,
that we thread
Then, we stimulated
to try to recreate the arrhythmia
He had a tiny wire
in a node in his heart,
quote-unquote, to fix the issue.
After that his heart started
And the arrhythmia never came back.
-[indistinct chatter]
[Pocho] He came out of it quickly,
He didn't talk about it much.
I never saw him worried, and I think he…
bottled up a lot of these emotions.
[over recording] I believe it was his way
[♪ curious music playing]
[indistinct chatter]
[Hernán] Sergio went to the Under-20
Messi was two years younger
and Sergio was three years younger.
And they spent a lot of time together.
When Leo was with him,
HERNÁN REGUERA
[Sergio] I knew he was more serious
He felt at ease being around me
We had a lot of trust between us
personal things with each other,
[crowd cheering]
[commentator] The Norwegian
Argentina and Nigeria are playing.
2005 FIFA U-20 WORLD CUP FINAL
[commentator] We're in the U-20 final.
Garay looks for Zabaleta,
Agüero drives into the box.
Agüero, Agüero, foul,
-[whistle blowing]
[Sergio] They foul me,
[commentator] Messi's about to take
Goal for Argentina! Messi!
[Sergio] So, I always tease him,
because I was the one
If it weren't for me,
And he cracks up laughing.
We always joke around like that.
"You won this because of me."
We tease each other that way, you know?
But in reality,
he's the one who always carried the team,
…I still like to tease him
"Well, I helped you out a bit, didn't I?"
[Leo] We constantly sought each other out.
It's a team sport, and you always depend
We're very different in character,
and instead of driving us apart,
He followed the rules.
The thing is,
If we had to be in our rooms by 11:00,
"Come on, let's go to the room."
We had to pay a fine
and I always teased him, saying,
[laughs]
He would just crack up,
So, we were always together…
[crowd cheering]
2005 … 2012
[announcer in English]
Manchester City and the Arsenal!
[in Spanish] With Arsenal,
It was a season that got off
[Sergio] But we lost against Arsenal.
[commentator 1] Arteta!
[commentator 2 in English]
[Pablo in Spanish] It seemed like
was getting away from us.
They were eight points behind,
[Sergio] We lost, and Mancini stormed in,
saying, "We lost the championship."
[Pablo] He came in and started saying
He told us that if we really wanted
like the Premier,
we wouldn't get anywhere
I started keeping an eye
and we had the game against United left.
I thought, "All right,
If we won,
After that, they'd have to lose one match,
so we'd be three points behind
[Hernán] In a conversation with Sergio,
"We're going to win the championship
His optimism and faith in the team
despite losing just two hours earlier.
ROUND 32
1ST MANCHESTER UNITED 79 POINTS
[♪ tense music playing]
[Sergio] We moved on to the next match,
[commentator 1 in English]
He did do! And how!
ROUND 33 MANCHESTER UNITED 79 POINTS
[Sergio in Spanish]
[commentator 2 in English] It's Agüero!
[crowd cheering]
[commentator 3] Manchester City
[commentator 2] It's Agüero!
Never in doubt!
ROUND 35 MANCHESTER UNITED 83 POINTS
[Sergio in Spanish] Next we faced United,
and it was the key match, so to speak.
[indistinct chatter]
[Pablo] Well,
and it was the key matches of the season.
This would allow us to overtake
and with the goal difference on our side,
meaning it would mostly depend on us
[Sergio] Maradona came to see the game.
It was an important match,
[commentator in English] And here,
is Diego Maradona.
[in Spanish] It was truly
especially considering
[crowd cheering]
[Pablo] Because Manchester City
Manchester United's rival.
The season prior,
but at that point,
[♪ intense music playing]
[crowd cheering]
[whistle blowing]
[commentator in English]
the sitting tenants.
Manchester City's night in the derby
[Sergio in Spanish] Derbies have always
because I also think about the fans.
All the media and everyone else claimed
[Martín] The match ends,
and everyone comes over.
-[crowd chanting] Sergio! Sergio! Sergio!
It wasn't just Sergio.
MARTÍN URGOITY
It was Sergio plus Maradona at that time.
He was in a committed
and had a child with her.
So, you start putting the pieces together,
and he handled that situation…
very naturally.
MANCHESTER UNITED 83 POINTS
[commentator in English]
on goal difference.
[Leonel in Spanish] I never imagined
[Leonel] They reached the final match
it was… unbelievable.
The game kicked off the night before
were dealing with a new situation.
[indistinct chatter]
[in English] Oh, right in!
[Sergio in Spanish]
And on the final night, I said,
You know?
No one sent a message back or anything,
So, I thought,
That's when I began to realize
I went to bed,
[♪ tense music playing, concluding]
[Pablo] On game day,
[crowd cheering]
[Pablo] Everything pointed
being crowned champions that day.
[Sergio]
and we wanted to win against
[♪ tense music playing]
[Pablo] We were battling for the title
along with being up against
Both things at the same time.
[commentator in English]
And on this ground, this season,
[Sergio in Spanish] The truth is
Queens Park Rangers had a perfect plan,
[crowd cheering]
[Sergio] I remember it was a disaster.
I wanted to do something,
I could see my teammates
[commentator 1 in English]
Wayne Rooney has scored
Which means City must score.
[in Spanish] Adriana is very religious.
I remember she gave me
"If you want to wear it, you can.
I'm very positive."
Honestly, I had never worn anything
[commentator 2 in English]
It's in!
Relief! Relief!
[Sergio in Spanish]
We ended the first half
"All right, that's it.
[commentator 2 in English]
[in Spanish] Not many people remember
[commentator 1 in English] It's halftime
are winning,
courtesy of Pablo Zabaleta's shot.
[Pablo in Spanish]
I was starting to feel a bit selfish.
I thought, "Ugh, please,
I mean, I wanted my moment of glory.
Then the second half starts,
[commentator 2 in English]
And Cissé scores
[Pablo in Spanish]
Manchester United was winning their match.
Even worse, you could feel the desperation
because it was already the second half,
Then, during a corner kick,
that second goal ended up backfiring,
[commentator 2 in English]
they mount an attack, it's Traoré…
Beyond Zamora. Oh, it's in!
Unbelievable!
[Pablo in Spanish]
[commentator 2 in English]
[Hernán in Spanish]
I don't think anyone believed
The stadium felt lifeless.
[commentator 3 in English]
blows the final whistle.
And it means that Manchester United
and now face a wait, an anxious wait,
before they know whether they are
[Sergio in Spanish]
[commentator 4 in English] And Clichy
I felt uncomfortable on the field.
At one point, I looked at the clock.
"That's it," I said, "The match is lost."
[Leonel] And Sergio wasn't there.
If anyone needed to be subbed out,
He hadn't touched the ball at all.
Mancini used up all his substitutions
and left Sergio on the field.
[Pablo] There's a remarkable ability
in the game and remain present.
When the ball goes to the corner,
"It's a chance!"
[in English] Come on, come on!
[commentator 4] Silva. Dzeko scores!
Four minutes to save themselves!
Four minutes to find their crown!
[Sergio in Spanish] I grab the ball
"I just need one chance. Just one."
[Pablo] Fate needed to put that final shot
I thought to myself,
if I don't go for the ball?"
I had told Mario to stay close
[commentator 4 in English] Balotelli!
[in Spanish] "Pass it, pass it, pass it."
And right there, from the ground,
Out of the corner of my eye,
[Pablo] He stepped on his heel.
I mean, maybe someone else
They would have thrown themselves down.
I wanted to shoot across the goal.
That's the worst part of it all.
I hit it a bit in the middle,
[crowd cheering]
[commentator 4] Agüero!
-[♪ suspenseful music playing]
[crowd cheering]
[commentator 4 in English]
He's won the league with 90 seconds
United's game was over,
they had it, they've had it stolen back!
It's just the most extraordinary scenario
Where does football go from here?
[Leonel in Spanish] He only touched
and he scored.
Unbelievable. What a joy!
[Adriana] I prayed so much
I was kneeling, crying, and giving thanks.
He is enlightened.
[indistinct chatter]
[Sergio] I went to the locker room
while everyone else was celebrating.
They hugged me and thanked me, you know?
but… in my mind,
[in English] Come on, City!
[Sergio in Spanish] So, the whole thing
confusing me even more.
[♪ intriguing music playing]
[Sergio] I don’t know how to explain
that it’s a bit complicated
that it’s not a solitary sport, you know?
I kept thinking about Zabaleta or Dzeko.
They had something to do with this too.
[crowd cheering]
I don’t think Sergio even realizes
without a doubt.
Just imagine how many years they waited
[Sergio] I took it that way
I celebrated everything,
back to training
[Pablo] This is where he says…
"This is my place. I'm going
[crowd chanting] City! City!
[exhales]
Hey!
PEP GUARDIOLA
-[crew member] How's it going?
Arriving at a site,
In the beginning,
the players look at you
"Oh, let's see what this guy is about.
Or, "Can I meet his expectations?"
that if there was a standout player
That's when I realized that it would be…
a very challenging year with Guardiola.
[♪ intriguing music playing]
[♪ music concludes]