[thunder rumbling]
[Sergio] I never managed my finances.
23 YEARS OLD
[Sergio]
and I'd just play.
I got on the plane…
and there was quite
It really hit me.
what would happen to the money
[thunder rumbling]
[♪ reflective music playing]
[Sergio]
Benjamín would be left with nothing.
-[♪ dramatic music playing]
From behind. Come on, kids. Come on, kids.
-The foot, not the knee.
[trainer 1] The feet and the knee. Go, go.
[trainer 2] Come on,
-[whistle blowing]
Barely touch the ground, Dani.
Great work, everyone.
-[birds chirping]
"18 YEARS OLD"
[birds chirping]
I knew we were going to draw
SERGIO AGÜERO
-[indistinct chatter, cheering]
-[reporter] You, too. You, too.
[Diego] "I'm going out
I was there
At the moment,
DIEGO CAMPOS
I didn't know she was Maradona's daughter.
ADRIANA AGÜERO
-[indistinct chatter]
[photographer] Here, Diego!
The first thing I felt when they told me
"MIGUEL ÁNGEL GIL
was fear.
-[indistinct chatter]
[Miguel] The first thing you think is,
"Will he be able
It was risky because Diego
over such an important player
[indistinct chatter]
[Hernán] Gianinna perfectly understood
She'd been with her father
"HERNÁN REGUERA
so it wasn't a difficult transition.
[Sergio] Diego didn't come much.
he drew the attention
because everyone knew him.
At no time did I ever apologize to anyone.
If I ever have to apologize to anyone,
[Martín] He was never in the spotlight
and our goal was to keep it like that.
MARTÍN URGOITY
[♪ reflective music playing]
We were at a barbecue
He tells me. And… and I was like,
LUCAS "POCHO" FERNÁNDEZ
[laughs] I mean, it was crazy because,
on top of everything,
[birds chirping]
[Sergio] The problem
Diego was intimidating too, right?
[♪ quirky music playing]
[Sergio] We said,
"And you'll tell your dad."
"I'm not going to tell him."
He stood up. "You're fucking with me,"
And he kind of looked at everybody
Claudia told him, "No, man,
[chuckles] He left the house.
And well, I stayed and said,
[♪ sentimental music playing]
[Sergio] But he was always very respectful
the life I had with his daughter.
[Martín] There were only a few months left
"Sergio, did you buy him anything?
Well, yeah, then he started shopping,
and obviously,
When you create so many problems
[commentator 1 over PA] And the ball!
[commentator 2, over PA] Goal!
-[commentator 1 over PA] Agüero acts…
…that takes your focus off
[Sergio] Being a parent,
When the baby is born,
that's when you really learn
With the left leg. Good. That's good.
-Great, so great.
Ah, right. You had a great time, you said?
Or when I had to go to play
I didn't see him for 10 days.
Or when I had to go to preseason
[cheers, giggles]
[Sergio] I mean, raising my son
It was difficult.
[crowd cheering indistinctly]
[Sergio] I wanted to play football,
"I have to look after him, right?
There. Go on, go on. That's it!
-[Benjamín speaks indistinctly]
And there goes Benjamín,
He's going to shoot.
[birds chirping in distance]
[reporter over TV] Leo was very small
but was always first
That's my dad.
[on TV] He'd take me there early.
After that, I'd play at another club.
-[Sofía] Really? Wow!
SOFÍA CALZETTI
When I watched him play
I wanted to hit it with my left foot.
BENJAMÍN AGÜERO
-That's true.
I had my cousins, but I only saw them
you know what I mean?
Yeah, that's true.
When he'd come to Manchester,
After I came back to the house,
the first thing he'd do when he saw me,
And of course, he wanted to play.
-And I was sore all over.
But I told him: "Well, come on, come on,
But of course, it took while.
[interviewer] Tell me two good things
-No, no, one bad and one good.
I don't know.
You don't call me that much.
A bad one is
-[Sergio] Now, the good one.
that every time I'm here with you,
and you always make me laugh.
[Sergio] That's good, huh?
Very good, huh?
-[swing creaks]
[♪ reflective music playing]
13 YEARS OLD
Before the kid would get there…
[dog barking in distance]
…he'd have to leave his home first.
Having a shower is important.
JOSÉ LUIS "LUIGGI" SERVIÁN
-[birds chirping]
-[♪ dramatic music playing]
[Hernán]
[crowd cheering]
A very skilled player, very powerful,
with a very, uh, very,
He made a huge difference.
[crowd cheering, applauding]
[Hernán] People talked about
at Independiente, called Agüero.
The moment we became his representatives,
that was a little more comfortable
[indistinct chatter]
[crowd cheering, applauding]
[♪ intricate music playing]
I knew I played well, but of course,
my old man didn't act like…
[insects chittering]
[Sergio] I'd finish a game,
was he'd grab me and take me with him.
So, that they wouldn't tell me,
That way, I'd maybe get confused
My old man was directly in control of me.
[Hernán] We talked about almost everything
Sergio was very, very quiet.
Always in a good mood and happy
He always liked to be with his family
On the weekends, Sergio would say,
"You? No.
JOSÉ "PEPE" SOSA
Very large family.
They adopted me
I lived with them for eight years.
Such a great family.
[Pocho] They were also there
And we just became good friends,
Uh, we're like…
-[seagulls squawking]
[indistinct chatter]
[Pocho]
and he immediately scored goals
-[whistle blowing]
[indistinct chatter]
He spent about two weeks,
in a selective team with Ruggeri.
Then, he was promoted to the first team.
And there, you could already see
that he'd never go back
That kid was going to keep going forward.
[athletes shouting indistinctly]
We wanted things to work out for him.
In the first division, right?
-[crowd cheering, applauding]
[Sergio] As the days and weeks went by,
But all I wanted to do was play.
[crowd cheers]
[Sergio] It all happened so fast.
[commentator 1 over PA]
[commentator 2 over PA]
35, Diego Ludueña.
[interviewer] Do you want to give yourself
by letting this boy debut?
Because he would be
If he's needed… if he's needed
No problems with that.
Come on, get it!
[commentator 1]
I was reaching for the ball.
[crowd chanting] Come on roo, come on roo,
[Pepe] At that moment,
-"Hey, go get the boy for me."
[Pepe] And he said, "Agüero, Agüero."
[commentator 2] It looks like
a historic event at Independiente.
[commentator 2] He's got a baby's face,
-[commentator 1] Well, he's going in, huh?
Sergio Agüero, 15 years old.
Sergio Agüero has been here
since he was nine years old.
[commentator 1] This is a historic event
who only just celebrated his birthday,
[commentator 2] Udinese's representatives
[commentator 1]
He left Celso Esquivel
Agüero's on the run. Agüero keeps going,
He got a bit carried away there.
If no one gets close,
Well played! He passed it off,
Quick play now to Cholito Guiñazú,
He shook off Piombo.
the little guy on the team.
[commentator 2] Good work
[crowd cheers]
[commentator 1] Time's up in this match.
right before the throw-in,
Mr. Furchi makes the good
FINAL RESULT
[Hernán] He made his debut
and between 2003 and 2005,
He played for either the reserves
[horn blaring]
[Sergio]
if I remember correctly.
[♪ dramatic music playing]
We were there that day.
It was… it was wild.
MAURICIO DEL CASTILLO
[Sergio] When I went to the stadium,
[cell phone beeps]
[Sergio] It rang, and it was Mario,
a fan of Independiente and a friend
"Hey, if you don't kick
when I see you, I'm going to slap you."
And, all angry, he kept saying,
I used to never kick
Anyway, I went in with that in my head,
"I should try kicking
[commentator 1 over PA]
that lead down. Once again,
the left-footed Insúa
Sergio Agüero plays well. Agüero holds on,
-Goal!
[♪ euphoric music playing]
They caught me there. Hey! [chuckles]
[commentator 2 over PA] Look at the speed…
and distance of Agüero's shot
That's when I had my moment
[thunder rumbling]
[Sergio] It really hit me.
what would happen to the money I'd made
Benjamín would be left with nothing.
[♪ sentimental music playing]
[seatbelt clicks, clatters]
[Sergio] As soon as I landed,
He calls me out of nowhere and says,
"What happens to Benjamín?"
So, I explained it to him.
And he says to me, "Well,
"He's the account holder."
I had to… I had to start managing
[indistinct chatter]
[Sergio] I opened up a personal account.
But when he found out
without telling him, yeah, he got angry.
[♪ tense music playing]
[Sergio] He called me, and we argued.
He said,
and not the usual full amount?"
"I want to control my money."
"You have yours, and I have mine."
And he cut me off.
LEONEL DEL CASTILLO
[Sergio] We haven't spoken for a long time
He made it very clear,
"It'll be this way with my siblings."
We then created specific parameters
[Hernán] A certain tension develops
after two or three people
But his father also understood
He took control for not only himself,
and, well,
[Martín] Always, since the beginning,
As he understood more,
And he became another person.
He would talk about stocks,
or he would competently talk
I think that made him feel really good.
[♪ reflective music playing]
[Leonel]
I made him earn more
So, why couldn’t I be there?
[on TV] He never included me in anything
who had nothing to do with us.
And I always asked him why.
Well, anyway. I think he should have…
…at least included me
I think that’s when Sergio
"Dad," there are other people
But he did business with them,
Yeah, I always left him out
because when something goes wrong,
I always told him…
Instead of always looking
for me and getting involved
He should just be a dad, right?
[crowd cheers, applauds]
[Hernán] Falcioni gave him
"17 YEARS OLD"
and he played as a starter all year.
[commentator over PA]
He passes it to Pusineri.
Here comes Kun. Shoots at the goal.
[crowd shouting indistinctly]
[Pocho] He became someone else
someone with much more confidence.
[crowd cheers]
[interviewer] When can Agüero take
-Huh?
Well, I think he should get--
-[interviewer] One week?
[both laughs]
[commentator over PA]
to play against River Plate.
-[crowd cheering]
[Hernán] We met with several clubs,
two teams from Milan.
And the last one was Atlético Madrid.
We were going through a difficult time
We'd just gone
and for me,
to compete with the big teams again.
And Sergio, I believe, had the qualities
He truly did.
[commentator over PA]
Agüero with a second shot.
-Goal!
[Hernán] Miguel Ángel Gil was the only one
who was absolutely convinced
as he was taking the best player
[commentator] Agüero!
At that moment, it wasn't a simple
[♪ uplifting music playing]
[Miguel] Independiente in Avellaneda,
had other transfer targets in mind.
On the other hand,
as it turned out, a diamond in the rough.
So, certain risks had to be taken
We presented their offer to Sergio.
[Adriana] He said, "Mom,
And I said, "That's great, son,
Then, he said, "But I'm going to Europe."
He said, "Abroad. It's far away."
I replied, "Well,
And he said, "Yes."
He asked me, "What do you want?"
And I said, "No, what do you want?
I told him, "Whatever makes you happy
HUMID PAMPAS, ARGENTINA
[Miguel] I'll never forget it
because we took a private plane
and flew to the Humid Pampas,
When we were about to land,
I kept noticing that there was no runway,
and as we were touching down,
In the end, a very nice,
[Leonel] It was the team
and paid Independiente
And… and then we went there.
They talked so much
that they didn't…
that I hoped he would treat my son well.
And he told me not to worry,
[Sergio] On the other hand,
My dream was to be able, of course,
He was at a point where he was
[crowd cheering]
KUN 100% RED MAGIC
KUN: THANK YOU FOR YOUR MAGIC AND YOUR
KUN, THANK YOU
[Pocho]
He had a good time on the field
[♪ upbeat music playing over speakers,
♪ A poco que debutó ♪
-♪ Marado, Marado ♪
♪ La 12 fue quien coreó ♪
♪ Marado, Marado ♪
♪ Su sueño tenía una estrella ♪
[laughs]
♪ Llena de gol y gambetas ♪
♪ Y todo el pueblo cantó ♪
♪ Go, Kun, go, Kun ♪ [laughs]
♪ Nació la mano de Dios ♪
♪ Go, Kun, go, Kun ♪
♪ Llevó alegría en el pueblo… ♪
[Adriana] It's one thing to say it,
I was already mentally preparing myself
[♪ reflective music playing]
[Adriana] He didn’t want anything.
Then, he said yes.
I was nervous.
SERGIO'S 18TH BIRTHDAY
[Adriana] It was just family and friends.
And he was leaving the next day.
[all] ♪ Happy birthday to you
I remember that the family was a bit off
[Diego] I wasn't even sad.
to see what would happen.
We were in the kitchen, and he said,
"Mom,
I looked at him and said that…
[on TV] He sat down and said,
I replied, "No, no, son."
"This journey is yours, not mine."
[indistinct chatter]
[Adriana] He thought we were all going.
Yes, it was a surprise,
[on TV] …tough surprise.
I told him that this was his journey
and that he didn't have
He had to pursue his career,
and on the day
it would've been useless to cry.
And the truth is, we both held it in.
[♪ music concludes]
[airplane engine whirring]
[crowd chanting] Agüero.
[crowd chanting] Agüero, Agüero, Agüero…
[Emilio] I was responsible
We organized it in such a way,
"EMILIO GUTIÉRREZ MARKETING AND
when he came out of the terminal.
[crowd cheering, shouting]
-[camera shutter clicking]
[Emilio] I met a boy there
-[indistinct clamor]
[Emilio] A scared kid,
because he didn't know
or the number of people waiting outside.
[crowd chanting] Agüero, Agüero, Agüero!
Television cameras, journalists, fans.
[indistinct clamor]
[Emilio] It was a nightmare
[interviewer]
was something you never dreamed of.
No, honestly never.
[indistinct chatter]
[Miguel] I have been
Many footballers have come and gone,
and in the end,
The coaches told him
but he still had to come here and adapt.
European football is different
[indistinct chatter]
Competition, the pace of the game,
Here, the game is much faster,
-[birds chirping]
[Emilio] We all risked this investment
[crowd cheering]
[Hernán] The first six months were tough
because he wasn't playing much
He was a substitute.
He missed his family.
and he missed Buenos Aires.
[Leonel] When he arrived at Atlético,
I stayed with him
His mother stayed in Argentina
[Mauricio] We were missing
There were seven of us siblings,
was leaving, right?
I guess no parent
But, well, it was for his future.
At some point, I left and was gone
I think I didn't go back to Spain.
[indistinct chatter]
[Leonel] There was no one with him.
[Miguel] There was someone at the club,
who was there day and night,
I know in the beginning, it wasn't easy.
[player 1 speaks indistinctly]
-Here, you can't…
[Emilio] There was a time when he went
We talked on the phone all the time,
"You'll come on this date?"
When I went, after my daughter was born,
Then, I had to go back because otherwise,
He’s introverted.
I never knew when he was feeling down
[traffic whizzing]
[Emilio] I knew we were going
so I listened to all the programs
for him to get a good idea
But what I couldn’t control
was them having his father there
He will go down in history
and how the crowds cheer for him.
His name is Sergio.
but he becomes much more formidable
[presenters chanting] Kun, Kun, Kun, Kun…
[presenter 2] I imagine that someone
must be enjoying it, too.
He's also happy when he hears that chant
It's Leonel Agüero,
[Leonel over phone] Hello.
They called me and told me
that I had to say hello to him.
I said, "No, well, it’s been so long…"
I said. But I called him and…
[presenter]
How does the father of Sergio, Kun Agüero,
feel about everything
[Leonel] So happy, uh, so happy here.
The whole family is excited,
Well, we don't get to
But yes, we're always glued to the TV
keeping up with how he's doing.
[presenter]
Plus, he gets really happy
-[Leonel] Yes. Yes, yes.
[sobs]
-[Leonel] Well… We…
…We all… We all send him our regards.
[Emilio] No matter how well
you can never replace
I might not show it,
I had to… A week later, I left.
And I stayed with him.
Because I felt like
[sobs]
[♪ music concludes]
6 YEARS OLD
[♪ soft music playing]
[whistle blowing]
[fans cheering] Goal!
-[indistinct chatter]
I paid a lot of attention,
watching how he played
He could play well with both feet
I saw that and thought,
[Daniel] Leo was an amazing player.
[birds chirping]
[Daniel] He was a great footballer.
and a goal scorer.
DANIEL FRESCÓ
He was one of the standout players
on every team he played for
He played for San Martín de Tucumán
I think the closest he got
But when his first daughter was born,
[Leonel] I worked in a bakery.
[indistinct chatter]
[Leonel] On Sundays,
we would play football in front
Other teams would come and pay me to play.
which helped me skip work
[Daniel] Leo played in various tournaments
And he always took Sergio with him.
While he played,
Sergio would kick the ball around
At one point,
he started to notice that people
who, despite being so small,
-[indistinct chatter]
[Daniel] At one point,
-[trainer cheering] Goal!
…and told Leo, "I want him on my team."
[Leonel] I remember a man
"Bring him,
I told him, "No, let him be.
But they kept insisting
He started playing friendlies and such.
on Sergio, and take him to play football.
Teams from everywhere
People would come to me,
I never got to play professionally
And I thought, "Well, uh… maybe Sergio
[♪ music concludes]
-[whistle blowing]
[indistinct chatter]
2007 MADRID
[Hugo] Agüero already had experience
He’d even played
[trainer] Pick up the pace!
[Hugo] But we brought him
[trainer] They're far away.
[Hugo] I was a bit worried that
"HUGO TOCALLI
because he wasn't in the senior team,
But no, it was the exact opposite.
It felt like a challenge.
Try to achieve what my friend Leo did."
He'd done it in Holland
and the best player
[Hernán]
We would've advised him
since he'd already played
and the club didn’t want him to go either.
And they told me,
"You're in Europe, while most of the U-20
"If things go wrong,
you know all the criticism
Anyway.
[Hernán] That alone shows
to join the national team
-[trainer] Go, go, go.
[Hugo] I decided to give him
I saw that he wasn’t
He'd already transformed.
like a young man who was already
2007 CANADA U-20 WORLD CUP
It was the final match
We were losing one to zero.
[crowd cheering]
Tocalli told me that at some point,
and I had to seize that opportunity.
Banega was positioning himself to pass
The center-back
That's when I shouted, "Éver." Loudly.
That's the move that went wrong for him.
After the experience I gained in Europe,
I knew that goalies always think
So, I waited for the gap at the near post.
[commentator] There’s Kun!
Goal, goal, goal, goal,
He won all the awards. Yes, yes, yes.
It was an incredible joy for us,
especially to experience it with him.
The best part was knowing
and putting a little pressure on the club
[crowd cheering]
[Leonel]
I didn't tell him
I kept saying
I told him there were things
[commentator 1] It comes back to Kun.
He cuts inside, cuts there again.
What a goal! Goal, goal, goal, goal, goal,
[commentator 2] Against Ramis,
-[crowd cheering]
[commentator 4] There we have
[commentator 5] After the long ball,
who might score
Kun keeps going.
[crowd cheering, applauding]
[Sergio] The boost from the U-20 team
"I'll do my best
[crowd cheering, applauding]
[Rodrigo]
I believe he became
RODRIGO HERNÁNDEZ
For me it's hard to find a forward
from his time at Atlético Madrid
[commentator 1] Felipe leaves
Watch out for the space he left open.
[Rodrigo] He has a special talent
[commentator 2] Kun Agüero continues.
[Gerard] He was a special player.
GERARD PIQUÉ
It'd seem like
but suddenly, a ball would come to him,
and he'd show off his incredible ability
[Sergio] My playing style
I'm disconnected from the game.
Then, I'll try to quickly
2008 BEIJING OLYMPIC GAMES
-[indistinct chatter]
[Leo] The Olympic Games
from any other competition
LEO MESSI
[Leo] They had a huge impact on me.
We had a fantastic team,
We were very young
That's when our transition started,
"PABLO ZABALETA
and really reached a new level of maturity
where the best years
[♪ music concludes]
-[interviewer] Hello.
PEP GUARDIOLA
-[interviewer] What's up?
[announcer 1] It's official now.
[announcer 2 in English]
-[cameraman] This way, please.
2016 MANCHESTER
[announcer 3 in English] One of the most
Six trophies and six competitions
Pep Guardiola!
[crowd cheering]
[Pep in Spanish] When you first arrive
[in English] I need, uh,
[in Spanish] The league,
[in English] Ah, it's good, too.
[in Spanish] The language,
As a player, you know who Pep is
which he proved with Barcelona
Pep held a meeting with us
and was very straightforward,
It was as if he was saying,
It's simply about wanting you
about you having the same passion
At first, the players
"Oh, let's see about this guy.
Let's see if I can meet his expectations."
But clearly, at that time,
if there was one key player
And so,
[indistinct chatter]
NICOLÁS OTAMENDI
He has a tactical approach that few
[birds chirping]
He’s a coach who demands
[Pep in English] Move! It's okay!
Go! Look for space! It's there!
Good pass! Go, go, go, go! Yes!
[in Spanish]
he wanted me to initiate the press.
[indistinct chatter]
[Pep in English] Go! Pressure! Pressure!
[in Spanish] The issue was
and after running so many meters,
I ended up being too winded to attack.
[Pep] I wasn't asking him
but he had to do what was necessary
And from the very first day,
When it comes to scoring goals,
[Sergio] I focused on pressing
He started to find a solution to avoid
like the ones spanning 40 yards.
Then, it was about trying to score goals
-[♪ dramatic music playing]
[Sergio] The Champions League match
It was against Barcelona at Camp Nou,
I wanted to use a false nine
[Sergio] He called me to his room
"I wanted to tell you ahead of time
so it wouldn’t catch you
[indistinct chatter]
[Sergio] I started feeling a little upset
and got the impression
because he left me on the bench
to play as a false nine
[commentator] The moment
it’s four to zero for--
A tough blow for Pep Guardiola's City.
[crowd cheering]
[Sergio] I was quite upset, yes.
that this year with Guardiola
FULL TIME NEYMAR 89' MESSI 17' 61' 69'
It was a disaster.
Our plan didn’t work out at all.
Sergio, no matter what he does…
[indistinct chatter]
Feeling unimportant was a hard hit
[fans] Agüero, Agüero, Agüero, Agüero…
[indistinct chatter]
[Sergio] Every player knew
"You won’t be playing."
Then, two months later,
-[indistinct chatter]
Gabriel Jesus joined in January,
and he was just beginning
Pep would say, "Run there," and he'd run.
But Gabriel Jesus didn't--
The first year was tough.
[indistinct chatter]
Jesus came in, and he had to compete
[Sergio] I was surprised that he placed
when he arrived, suggesting that I might
I think the last match I started
and after that, Gabriel took over.
He was a young kid with a lot of ambition,
[crowd cheering]
[Sergio] We were set to play
when Gabriel Jesus got injured.
He glanced at the bench
As I'm taking off my gear,
"Come on, you wanted to play, didn’t you?
Right in front of all my teammates
He had this reaction like…
"Of course I want to play."
Because some players say,
and they burn out quickly,
[Sergio]
[commentator in English]
by a delighted Sergio Agüero!
[crowd cheering]
[commentator]
[Sergio in Spanish] Gabriel got injured.
I’ll have to take advantage
and prove that he was wrong, right?
-[♪ inspirational music playing]
[crowd cheering]
[♪ music concludes]
[♪ theme music playing]
[♪ theme music concludes]