ONE MONTH AFTER RETIREMENT
[♪ tense music playing]
[heart thumping]
[Sofía] We were sleeping.
and he suddenly said, "Wake up, wake up.
SERGIO'S PARTNER
My mind was all over the place,
or where to take him.
Plus, he's not someone
because he's a public figure.
So, I called Hernán, his agent.
"I don't know where to go.
SERGIO'S AGENT
She called me,
CARDIOLOGIST
[Roberto] He told me
He explained all of his symptoms,
because he'd gone through
before because he had...
He was afraid of it happening again.
[Sofía] And he told me,
So, I started counting it for him.
There were moments
It went "thump-thump," and then suddenly,
So, that "thump-thump" is like a single,
"FORMER FOOTBALLER AND ENTREPRENEUR"
is when it starts happening
and "thump-thump-thump."
They felt different
[Sofía] In two seconds,
"Lie down, calm down, try to rest.
And he settled down.
-[♪ dramatic music playing]
Extrasystoles are extra heartbeats.
[Sergio] It's annoying,
This was something different.
[Roberto] Most people do experience
It's just that, in my case,
So, other people also have it,
Fortunately, those episodes
Sergio has really mastered
From the outside, he always looks fine.
But what's going on inside of him?
What's going on inside his heart?
He's played professionally
A lot of pressure was placed
That's not common.
With Sergio, the stress
-Hello, hello, hello people. What's up?
MARCH 2023
Uh... Well, here I am
because I really don't have Internet.
-Hey, Kunis, it's two in the morning...
-What's going on? Sergio...
-I think...
I just felt a... a... a mini arrhythmia.
Right now?
I got scared because I don't really know
"CONTENT CREATOR"
because I've never experienced it.
Do you want to go to the doctor?
No, no, no. No, because I have a chip
Sergio has a chip,
let us check in anytime to see
and sends the data
-You noticed I seemed a bit off, right?
-Because I felt something like...
...uh, like out... out of sync.
And he had a minor arrhythmia,
Well, at the time,
but he wanted to keep going.
-Well, if I'm dying right now...
We'll wrap it up now, but it's fine.
-We're signing off.
[Ibai] He doesn't have a problem
how he's feeling
I think it's just because I'm starving
-since I haven't eaten anything.
I really think that's what it is.
This happened to him on live,
but he felt fine after
I think it's also important
and see how he deals with these issues.
Lots of people are already asking me
Don't worry about it. It's nothing.
I'm still here. [chuckles]
[cheering, indistinct chatter]
18 YEARS OLD
-[cheering, indistinct chatter]
[Sergio] The first goal I scored
But inside, I wasn't happy at all.
What I was thinking was...
"Why did I leave?"
I was alone.
He said, "Let's go for a drink."
I started to share
and... and...
And I told him
"MARKETING AND COMMUNICATIONS DIRECTOR,
if he wanted to reach the highest level.
It allows you to start
[Miguel] All the players coming
learn to adapt the same way.
They need to learn how to take care
His father had several habits
"PRESIDENT, ATLÉTICO DE MADRID"
that, in a highly competitive world,
My dad, every time he went to Spain,
-We are in Basilea.
We are in Ba... In-- In Switzerland, here.
[Sergio] We would stay up late,
Come on.
There, I hit you!
He'd go to training with me
-Maxi.
[Leonel] I'm filming that guy over there
[Sergio] He did things
[Leonel] Mister, say hi.
-Hello.
Go grab a coffee and leave us alone.
[Leonel chuckles] I'm filming the snow.
-Look at me filming.
-[Leonel] Uh...
[Leonel] Hold on. You. Hey!
I won't wait for you anymore, hmm?
I have to go train right now.
For example, Miguel Ángel Gil would say,
"You're not the player,
SERGIO'S FATHER
How can you tell an adult,
They're already grown up.
It was his for not going to bed.
Yeah, even if I'd sleep early,
It wasn't easy.
We asked Sergio to talk to him,
[Leonel] My fingers are frozen.
-[staff member 1 in distance] All right.
-[Leonel] Come on. Let's go this way here.
[Miguel] Changes started to happen after,
[indistinct chatter]
[Miguel] When he understood
he had two choices...
to be an average player despite his talent
Everything depended on his mentality.
He agreed to send money to his father
so his father could get out of his normal,
and step into the high-stakes world
-[crowd cheering]
Kun! Kun! Kun! Kun!
Kun! Kun! Kun! Kun! Kun!
[Martín] His parents had a good intuition
"SERGIO'S FINANCIAL ADVISOR"
about choosing the right people
[indistinct chatter]
[Martín] He would save money
or burn through it if he didn't.
This was when he was 18.
My role on the team was to say,
"Okay, here's my advice
"and most professional way possible."
But with Sergio alone, at that age,
The first time I became acquainted
was through Leonel, his dad.
Leo is quite a character in many ways.
He's very blunt and won't hold
Like everybody, he has an easygoing side
and a more difficult side.
But both of his sides are pretty extreme.
-[crowd cheering]
[Martín] Elite footballers experience
along with everything else
-that most of us can't even fathom.
I tried to get him to learn
so he wouldn't be completely clueless.
[indistinct chatter]
[reporter] Sampaoli, what's up?
ARGENTINA NATIONAL
Since the elimination
at the 2002 World Cup,
for Argentina's national team
2018 RUSSIA WORLD CUP
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[Hugo] The toughest one of all.
FORMER HEAD COACH ARGENTINA U-20
[sighs, indistinct chatter]
and we hadn't won anything since,
-[indistinct chatter]
[indistinct chatter]
[Leo] It was tough
through years of heavy criticism
We suffered a lot.
We gave each other strength and confidence
"LEO MESSI
to go out and play games.
[indistinct chatter]
[Leo] For most of his career
he felt like a substitute
with any coach to say,
"for the national team."
A FEW MONTHS BEFORE
[reporter] The national team is on alert
He had an arthroscopy on his left knee,
a month and a half ago.
[Sergio] I had surgery.
Sampaoli wanted me to go to Argentina
He wanted me to push myself,
There were still 20 days left
I mean, what was the point
The next day, the doctor told me,
"If you don't train enough,
"he thinks you won't be able
It was a lot of pressure.
It was totally unnecessary.
[indistinct chatter]
[Benjamín] To go hand in hand
[Sergio] We arrived at the World Cup
My knee, honestly, felt fine.
-[crowd cheering]
Agüero! [in English] One-nil!
Argentina off and running.
[chanting] The finals! The finals!
[Sergio] In the second match,
-[crowd cheering]
At halftime, Sampaoli asked me
He said, "All right, don't worry,
"so you can play
-[crowd cheering]
[Sergio] We were losing.
The second half starts, and 10 minutes in,
they announce that Pipa's
and I see my number
Suddenly, I'm the one being subbed off.
I looked at him like,
We ended up losing that match,
for the national team, right?
[indistinct chatter]
[Leo] We always tried to stay positive,
was that the coach
And Pipa, who was theoretically competing
at that time,
or so they say, and well...
[Nicolás] It was all a mess.
The atmosphere wasn't great, and that,
"MANCHESTER CITY PLAYER (2015-2020)"
whether you like it or not,
[reporter] Breaking news,
-and the coach has broken down.
We couldn't understand
[reporter] Honestly,
It's crazy it's happening
[Nicolás] It was challenging for us
[indistinct chatter]
[reporter] Everything is wrong, you know?
[Sergio] Why would he say one thing
He honestly never explained
which caused our communication
“WE STILL HAVE A CHANCE TOMORROW”
[reporter] Sampaoli mentioned that
so that's why it failed.
Do you agree
Let him say whatever he wants.
Then, people were saying
well, Leo, put the team together.
So Sampaoli didn't have control, etc.
That was completely false.
If Sampaoli didn't build the team,
-[crowd cheering]
Then, we played France. [chuckles]
Sampaoli didn't sub on any number nine
-[indistinct chatter]
We were losing 4-2,
he had no choice but to put me in.
-[commentator in English] Messi again...
[commentator] And Argentina
[in Spanish]
[crowd cheering]
[Adriana] When I see Sergio on the pitch,
I don't see him as a footballer...
He wouldn't talk about it to me,
I knew he was frustrated.
And that's when changes started
Sampaoli left Argentina.
Scaloni stayed with us.
He took on the responsibility
without having any experience
[Leo] It was painful.
It was the beginning of the end
their national team career together
[Sergio] And that's when I became one
along with Leo, Di María, and Otamendi.
[reporter] The number one in the world
-You can't argue with that.
23 YEARS OLD
[reporter] One day, would you like...
"Good afternoon to the best player
I wish, I wish.
[♪ tense music playing]
[Sergio] I'm working hard at Atlético,
and doing things right,
I wanted to win titles.
At Atlético,
than the two I'd already achieved.
[all cheering]
I was kind of upset with Miguel Ángel Gil
to compete against Madrid and Barça
[indistinct chatter]
[Sergio]
Uh, I put out a statement.
[reporter] Kun is living his final days
He has confirmed his intention
through a message on his personal website,
where he expresses his gratitude
of his personal life at the club
He has asked the club to consider,
the offers that other teams
[Sergio] The fans were very upset
UNGRATEFUL MERCENARY
[reporter] Would you change the name
I'm thinking about removing the name.
[reporter] And now,
Well, I'll throw it away.
Once this match is over,
...because the media
"Agüero is very close
"Real Madrid already
-[indistinct chatter]
[Miguel] In the end,
like Sergio to stay there.
[indistinct chatter]
You need to adjust and find a balance
He has a release clause
which a couple clubs in Europe
[Sergio] Miguel Ángel Gil came
And he told me, "You're not going to leave
To tease him, I'd say,
"then we should try to work it out."
He didn't want me to leave.
-[reporter] All right.
Nervous? Nervous? Yes? No?
[Sergio] I was young. I was 23,
[indistinct chatter]
-Seriously! [laughs]
[Sergio] Before traveling
I told that to the press at the airport.
[indistinct chatter]
I want to leave the club and... and...
I had five wonderful years here,
I want to thank the club
they showed me.
All I can say is that the club knew
So, it's their problem if...
[indistinct chatter]
[Miguel] I received a call
They told me they wanted
and the first thing I did
and call someone
-Khaldoon Al Mubarak, City's president.
[Miguel] I told him that I had a player
in Europe and that I couldn't allow him
He told me he was in Los Angeles.
So, I took a flight from Madrid
I was playing in the Copa América.
[crowd cheering]
[♪ uplifting music playing]
[crowd] Messi, Messi, Messi!
Agüero, Agüero, Agüero!
Valdano calls me and says,
It was Real Madrid.
The thing is, I was at Atlético,
"Hello, Sergio, how are you?
"I'll do everything possible
I said... [hesitates]
I told him,
"All of you should talk,
[Miguel] I went to dinner
It was an Italian restaurant
We tore off a piece of paper,
that was kind of like a letter of intent.
We both signed it.
They were convinced they wanted him.
And Sergio definitely wanted to play
[Sergio] The Copa América ends.
When we arrive in Manchester,
and on the plane, he... [chuckles]
he kept saying to me, "Can I negotiate
[indistinct chatter]
[Sergio] And he says, "No, because look,
"and everyone knows you're going
-"So, what if we say no?"
[indistinct chatter]
[Sergio] Because if you're already there
for your signing they'll look bad.
[indistinct chatter]
[Sergio] They'll have to figure it out.
And then, they said,
He looked at the first three
"No, I don't like this number.
That was pretty unexpected.
And at one point, I said,
And Sergio told me,
And I said, "We're leaving,
"and from there,
[Sergio] We arrived at the hotel,
"If I get you a bit more,
-[chuckles] He told me.
They offered almost the same
to go to a place that's cold...
that speaks a different language,
They had to modify the contract,
the lawyer couldn't hold back
"I can't believe what's happening.
I mean, it was really good.
At one point, I told my dad, "That's it.
It's done." And...
The number we wanted eventually appeared.
In the end, the contract was finalized
which was just a little more.
He was my agent for a day,
what he told me to do after. [laughs]
[♪ tense music playing]
THREE YEARS LATER
[cellphone ringing]
[Sergio] I was at City
He said, "I wanted to congratulate you,"
Then, he said, "Actually, I wanted
"that I should've told you before.
"I want to apologize because I regret
"on the national team."
2010 SOUTH AFRICA WORLD CUP
[commentator]
to really cement that place
and they're queuing up again here.
Germany has three!
Germany is going to the semifinals!
[Sergio] "I was an idiot,"
A FEW WEEKS BEFORE THE 2010 WORLD CUP
ARGENTINE FOOTBALL ASSOCIATION
[reporter] Let's go over the list
selected for the World Cup.
Messi, Higuaín, the starters,
FORWARDS
[reporter] Tevez, Milito,
Being called up to the national team,
[shouts indistinctly]
[Nicolás] In 2010,
It was all very exciting
Today, we're in the World Cup.
excuse my language, ladies, suck it.
Go on and keep sucking it.
Kun!
Fideo!
Come here!
[Nicolás] Sergio was always cracking jokes
He was such a pain. [laughs]
-[indistinct chatter]
[Javier] There you go. There you go!
[Nicolás] Obviously,
But it's the coach who decides.
Only eleven can play.
And he wasn't picked for the starting.
But he was always a positive person,
And that always helps the team.
And some were saying that
"SERGIO'S FRIEND"
because he was dating Maradona's daughter.
I bet that was probably uncomfortable
[laughing]
The coach, after hearing all of that
"Do I call him up again or not?
[commentator in English] To really
And they're queuing up again here.
Germany has three!
Germany is going to the semifinals!
Argentina is going out!
The whistle of the referee...
It was a very painful moment for everyone,
especially, with all the commotion
[commentator in English]
The silence was deafening,
and the entire
The only sound you could hear
[shutter snaps]
That day, he said that
I mean, everyone was really angry.
SERGIO'S FRIEND
But after a while,
[Sergio] There were times
But right away, I was already thinking,
"I have to keep going,"
because that's how football is.
You have to keep thinking about
We play every three days,
so we can't stay happy
What does it say here?
Benja Agüero.
Oh, Benja Agüero!
-Again!
Should I sign here?
-There.
[Sergio] I might be feeling down,
or a really bad game,
but lifting him up or listening
I think that's something
Blow him a kiss.
-Mwah! [chuckles]
[Sergio] At that time,
In England, it was good to play
[indistinct chatter]
[Sergio] But we barely had any rest.
I think being there with my family
[indistinct chatter]
[Sergio] The reality is that
The tiger!
-[Gianinna exclaims] Yay!
with Benja's mom.
I enjoyed that time
-[Sergio family member] The castle!
[laughs]
[Sergio] Until, well, there came a time
And that separation meant
that Benjamín was going to live
We agreed that he'd come to Manchester,
I'd rarely get to see him.
But every time he came,
[♪ acoustic rock music playing]
[Sergio] And when he left,
I tried to stay strong
I'd drive back from the airport
because I had to wait to see him again,
[Benjamín] To ten.
-To ten? Yes.
[both chanting]
[Sergio] Even to this day, when he leaves,
"Here we go again."
[speaks indistinctly]
[Young Benjamín]
-[speaks indistinctly]
[Diego] Benjamín is everything.
-[exclaims]
[chuckles]
He calls me on the phone and says,
[speaks indistinctly, laughs]
So, he tells me, "Babu, let's go
-"Okay, man."
He-- [hesitates] He used me to get cars.
[all laugh]
[Hernán] Sergio's relationship
Diego cared a lot for Benjamín.
[Diego] To the goal!
Hand, hand!
Penalty, penalty!
[Gianinna] But he's the goalkeeper!
[cheers] Hey, whoa! Go on, Benja, go, go!
-[dog barking at distance]
he wanted to see Benja, I obviously,
[dog barking]
[Sergio] He fulfilled his role
of father-in-law and Benjamín's
[loud cheering]
[audience chanting, whistling]
[chanting continues]
[commentator] Maradona didn't see
He's just seen his daughter
[commentator]
When Benjamín is there, it changes
-[commentator 1] Maradona is crying.
25 NOVEMBER 2020
[Sergio] I was in Greece for a game,
I saw a message from Benja saying,
Diego had passed away. [inhales deeply]
[♪ somber instrumental music playing]
[Sergio]
[indistinct chanting]
[news reporter in English] Even in death,
flooding the streets.
[reporter in Spanish] The car carrying
[Sergio] Aside from being Diego,
and I couldn't be with him...
I called him and said,
And he said, "No, I'm fine.
And I thought to myself,
At such an early age,
I think he processed his grief on his own.
He stayed strong
[indistinct chatter]
[Leonel] The English league is tough.
Tall players going up against
The defenders are huge.
[indistinct chatter, cheering]
[Sergio] At that time, for United,
starting to have a rival
didn't sit well with them, right?
[commentator in English]
Negredo into the middle,
Sergio Agüero does it again!
From close range!
Negredo.
Tangling with Vidić.
Over to the back post!
[cheering, whistling]
[Sergio] I already scored a lot of goals
And for me, personally,
-[♪ sentimental music playing]
[Pablo] To win a championship,
"MANCHESTER CITY PLAYER (2008-2017)"
who guarantees you
[crowd cheering, whistling]
[Pablo] Only a few players are capable
[players cheering]
[Sergio] After two years,
really put us in a position to challenge
who was another strong competitor.
[Pablo] Come on!
One more, that's it!
[players exclaiming,
[Sergio] And that was our goal,
to start winning titles so the club
[cheering, whistling]
[Sergio] My mom and dad would always go
-[singing indistinctly]
He loves being there,
It's like it's also his win, you know?
I could see you greeting half the crowd.
He must be thinking, "I took him
"I'm like Sergio,
He told me that
but he didn't have the luck I had.
"Because I went everywhere with you.
[cheering, whistling]
[reporter in English]
we've had in Manchester. Great to see
No, it's fantastic, uh...
The fans City, always,
Uh, fantastic on the pitch and here.
We have a... a good team.
-[laughs]
-[in Spanish] Oh! I tried! I tried.
[Sergio over TV]
Oh, you're laughing, huh?
If I speak English, I speak English.
[speaks indistinctly]
[Hernán] The dynamic started to shift,
and City began to see itself
no longer the little brother
6 MONTHS LATER
PRE-MATCH VS. NEWCASTLE
[Sergio] I wasn't at my best.
I spoke with Manuel
"HEAD COACH MANCHESTER CITY (2013-2016)"
and told him I'd play as long as I could.
I wasn't at a 100%.
We started off losing.
[commentator in English]
[Sergio] Before the first half ended,
[Sergio] And the second half kicked off.
[commentator in English] Newcastle United
And within fifteen minutes,
[commentator in English] It's a day
[Sergio in Spanish] Every ball I touched
[commentator in English]
[crowd cheering, applauding]
[Sergio in Spanish] In my head,
about how many players
Or seven.
There were still 25 minutes left.
And the next thing I saw
[commentator in English] We have seen
[Sergio in Spanish]
I mean, I kept thinking,
has scored six goals? I don't know,
I don't think anyone had.
I was injured, but I thought
You always imagine
[Manchester City player] Thank you!
[Nicolás] The first day I arrived...
He lied to me about the weather.
"It's just a passing cloud."
[chuckles] ... just...
Several of us were Argentinians,
uh, a bit more enjoyable.
[Pablo] Sergio is a very cheerful person.
Deep down, he truly lives for the game.
He's someone who's used to scoring goals.
There's a lot of pressure
These players live
and that's what makes them different.
[Sergio] It was a tough match.
We had to win
85TH MINUTE
[Sergio] And we were struggling
Xabi Alonso was trying
-[crowd cheering, whistling]
Oh, he took too much of a risk there!
-Agüero! Can he level? Yes, he can!
88TH MINUTE
[commentator in English]
in frustration.
[in Spanish] Kompany kicked it upfield.
[commentator in English] You think
Premier League title...
It was the way City liked to do it.
They could do it again
Agüero, he's done it again!
A hat trick for Sergio Agüero!
[Sergio in Spanish]
[commentator in English]
[in Spanish] I'm sure Pep wasn't happy
[indistinct chatter, shutters clicking]
[Sergio] The Champions League wasn't easy.
[Pablo] Manchester City's owners
[Manuel in English] Oh, tomorrow,
[Pablo in Spanish] ...to win
Focus, focus.
[Pablo] For us, it was also about saying,
"We have a team that can compete
"and we need to reach the final."
[speaking indistinctly]
[Nicolás] The club had never reached
Playing against Real Madrid
[Manuel in English] Definitely.
[Nicolás in Spanish] We were completely
[Nicolás] These are the matches
[♪ sentimental music playing]
[Sergio] Scoring goals isn't easy...
The more desperate you get
"MAY 4TH, 2016 MADRID"
and the more ambitious you feel
the harder it becomes...
because the pressure
I was pretty nervous.
It'd happened to me years ago.
Suddenly, my heartbeat started beating
-[♪ music swells]
[Roberto] He called me saying
-some irregular heartbeats.
Throughout all these years,
-[cheering, whistling]
[commentator in Spanish]
-Kun's shot, what a goal!
[Sergio] So many things just pile up.
[indistinct chanting]
[Sergio] He told me to rest more,
"You need to try to relax."
Everything flared up a little bit more
since I was worried
[speaking indistinctly]
[cheering, whistling]
[commentator] Agüero... Agüero!
[commentator in English]
And the Champions League dream is over.
[Sergio in Spanish]
my extrasystoles, which I usually have,
[reporter in English] This new,
unknown virus has killed 4,500 people
and infected 125,000 around the world.
[reporter 2 in English]
in Europe have been put on hold,
and that includes
[birds chirping]
[in Spanish] We were going through
with so much free time...
He used to not even know
but one day, he started streaming.
[Sergio] Come on, jump up. Come on, man.
Come on, come on, come on.
here it comes. No!
[Sofía] He'd sit down and talk
I'm so bad at this.
[Sofía] People started to enjoy
-Here, Marito.
-Take it, Marito! What's wrong, Marito?
What, you think that I'm not going
[Marito laughs]
I've always loved playing video games.
One day, my brother, Mauri, told me,
"and record yourself
I said, "Well, listen." I told him
"SERGIO'S BROTHER"
there's a platform that lets you
Goal! [laughs]
One day, another streamer found out
I was streaming.
And I started seeing
from the side, and I was like,
And I noticed that the view counter
People started asking me questions,
Independiente enrolled me
I was used to public schools before that.
No way, on the second day,
[♪ comical rock music exclaims]
I started to enjoy it,
because it was almost like therapy
I said, "Sofi, I'm streaming today."
And she looks at me and says,
I don't know what that laugh means.
When I played football, I didn't, I mean,
-[speaks indistinctly]
[Sofía] Sergio has always been eager
He's surrounded himself with people
ADVISOR FOR SERGIO'S NEW BUSINESS VENTURES
He started getting business offers
received as a football player.
"Why are they proposing this to me?
He's a really creative guy
very much in line with the new generation.
[reporter] Kun Agüero presents
a new organization in the world
[Matías] He decided to follow
"Well, I'll give it a try. Why not?"
Hello, YouTube people, how's it going?
Now, I'm going to show you
[indistinct chatter]
[Matías] It was partly coincidence
He started to sense that his retirement
Not too close, but close enough for him
about his life after football, I think.
To the people here on YouTube,
for hitting a million, uh, subscribers
Streaming was like a distraction
By the time I finished streaming,
I'd be dead tired after all that talking
-[Ibai] But, anyway.
If Guardiola saw this,
30% possession. Oh, my God.
No, no, no, he'd lose his mind.
We were concerned, more than anything,
"Hey, don't lose focus. You're still
[♪ intriguing upbeat music playing]
[Sergio] Ever since that injury.
I've been feeling pain in my calf,
I was training, then had to stop one day.
It just kept getting more difficult,
and Pep didn't know what to make of it.
[Pep] I always tell the players one thing.
"I'm the only person in your entire life
"who'd tell you something
[indistinct chatter]
"Because you know what's going to happen?
"you'll still be there, but I'm the one
"So, I want to stay here.
"I need to get the best out of you."
Sometimes getting
keeping him on the bench for a day,
It's to make him angry,
-[indistinct chatter]
[Sergio] Actually, I was going to recover
But by then,
[♪ music concludes]
[♪ theme music playing]
[♪ theme music concludes]