[indistinct chatter]
[in English] Okay, guys,
uh, for all the stuff from my car.
-And now it's the winner.
-Yeah, now it's the winner.
[players cheering]
-[Sergio] Ally!
[indistinct clamor]
[Sergio in Spanish]
"SERGIO AGÜERO FORMER FOOTBALL PLAYER
I talked to… to Leo.
LEO MESSI ARGENTINA NATIONAL TEAM PLAYER
-[♪ gentle music playing]
And he told me, "Why don't you tell
I think we might need a striker
MORE THAN A CLUB
He had a lot of offers
they were much better than Barcelona's.
And in the end,
when we’d get to share our daily lives
which was something really special for us.
[staff member in English]
[in Spanish] Playing with Leo
and being able to go into the World Cup
in the best way possible,
[reporter] Leo Messi
and retire at Barcelona,
Some people were saying
would obviously help him,
"'GERARD PIQUÉ
you know, stay,
-[indistinct chatter]
[Sergio] Then, well,
Here comes Beto, here's Beto, here's Beto,
He asked me, "Are you coming to Barça?"
He'd be happy if I was,
so we could stream together more
EPISODE 04 TRIUMPH
[reporter] What was an open secret
"MAY 31ST, 2021"
was finally confirmed.
-is now official.
[reporter] The Argentine striker will wear
after spending the last decade
IBAI LLANOS CONTENT CREATOR
We were at my house
and suddenly, I started seeing
that, apparently,
negotiations around Messi's
I texted Leo, and he said,
And then, I was like-- I mean,
I asked him, “But what happened?"
It didn't work out,
I was trying to find a way
but I didn't want to bother him
when he was having a hard time
[indistinct chatter]
THANKS FOR EVERYTHING MESSI
[Ibai] Sergio asked me to go to dinner.
Obviously, it never crossed my mind
and even less so after he announced
-[indistinct chatter]
-Ibai! Kun! Ibai! Ibai!
[Sergio] I was trying to be there for him
and joking around a little
I told him not to worry,
that we'd still play together
so that was fine.
But inside,
[Ibai] There was a moment
when everybody suddenly started crying.
It's like when your parents are arguing,
[chuckles] You can't do anything.
It wasn't my fault it didn't happen.
SEE YOU SOON
[Leo] It didn't work out.
which surprised everyone,
when I told him about it.
first for me because I couldn't continue
and then for him, because we couldn't play
[indistinct chatter]
[staff member] Come on, good,
Come on, go. No ball.
There, there. One, two, three. And out.
[Gerard] And there was a training session
[staff member]
[Gerard] It seemed like he was dizzy.
He didn't feel so good.
He had to stop training with the team.
[indistinct chatter]
-Yes.
[Sergio] I didn't feel like I used to.
I felt weird.
I had a check-up and everything,
FCBARCELONA
-[indistinct chatter]
2021 BARCELONA VS. REAL MADRID
[Sergio] El Clásico, Barcelona-Madrid.
I've watched Barcelona-Real Madrid
First Clásico, man. [inhales deeply]
-[Benjamín] Nervous?
-[Benjamín] It's Real.
-[crowd cheering]
[Sergio] After I was subbed on,
Then suddenly, I scored a goal.
[crowd cheering]
[Sergio] It looked like it'd end in a tie,
since, well, there was only a minute left,
[indistinct chatter]
[family member] Benja?
First goal.
[family member]
At least…
I don't care how it ends.
[family member] Forget it.
[Sergio] And I started thinking, "Okay,
so the show starts now."
But the show that came
It was a strange couple of days,
OCTOBER 30TH, 2021
[Sergio] I experienced symptoms
I was thinking, "I'm getting older."
[Adriana] Sergio seemed more serious.
ADRIANA AGÜERO SERGIO'S MOTHER
The atmosphere really felt… off.
[crowd chanting]
BARCELONA VS. ALAVÉS
[Sergio] Then what happened, happened.
I jumped to head the ball.
Everything I saw was blurry
I saw these wavy blue lines,
[crowd cheering]
[Sergio] My heart was racing.
I felt like I was suffocating.
[indistinct chatter]
I tried to calm down and stop thinking.
[pants softly]
It lasted for about two, three minutes.
And then, it kind of stopped.
[indistinct chatter]
[crowd cheering, whistling]
I didn't feel scared at that moment
"All right.
and I'll get back to--
[rain pattering]
[Sofía] It felt like time had stopped.
It was completely silent.
Then, we were told
SOFÍA CALZETTI SERGIO'S PARTNER
That's when we really understood
[indistinct chatter]
[Roberto] I got a call
I said, "Look,
is conduct an electrophysiological study
And consult with Dr. Brugada after."
ROBERTO PEIDRÓ CARDIOLOGIST
Josep Brugada is globally
Similar to the first procedure
many years ago,
but it wasn't
we'd previously addressed.
It was another arrhythmia,
This was a more complicated arrhythmia.
[bed whirring]
[Sofía] During those days,
He closed himself off.
He didn't speak much,
It felt like he was distancing himself
[sobs] And it broke me
[Roberto] We don’t know what triggers it.
So, I asked him
since I knew
And he said yes, that he was, well,
that he was going
TEN DAYS BEFORE
-Let's go…
[Sergio] Let's go.
[Benjamín] I can understand
[Sofía] He'd really gotten into top form.
He'd reached the same weight
and he was really pumped
But internally,
[Matías] And, above all, he was upset
[indistinct chatter]
[Matías] He was falling apart.
MATÍAS PORTELA
Still, if you saw him in a stream,
but that's his…
but you can still see through him,
[♪ upbeat rhythmic music playing,
I used to listen to this back home, man.
I need to take you to back there.
[chuckles softly]
Mom, come here.
[Sergio] No, no, I just said he was ugly.
-[Sofía] What a jerk.
-He wasn't ugly. Don't be mean.
-[Mauricio] Come on, Mom, say something.
No. You were cute, my baby.
-[all laughing]
[Mauricio] Yeah, I was ugly. I was.
Honestly, bro. I freaked out.
-[Adriana] You're such a jerk.
[Mauricio] You're not
[Sofía] They were always really tight.
Their parents' separation
[indistinct chatter]
[Sofía] Sergio also felt the weight
It hurt him somehow.
You know what I do?
You know when you're low
It-- It's like you need to just lay
TEN DAYS LATER TEKNON MEDICAL CENTER
[Leonel] I hadn't spent time with him
and I was living in Argentina.
"LEONEL DEL CASTILLO SERGIO'S FATHER"
"Do you want me to come over?"
It might've…
but since I noticed my mom
having my dad around
[Sofía] They'd just finished
"You know, if you were my son,
[Adriana] His world was falling apart.
I think he was afraid to sleep
because he was afraid
He told me, "Roberto,
Retiring right now wouldn't be that bad."
I said, "Look, Sergio, I think it's time.
And honestly, that'd make me feel
And he said, "I feel the same.
And I said, "And I'm very proud
You've had an amazing career."
-[indistinct chatter]
2021 2017 MANCHESTER
-[Sergio] All good?
[Sergio] I really wanted to continue
But I wasn't sure if I'd get
I knew it'd be hard for me the next year
I told my agent
I asked Hernán to let me leave.
[Hernán] He had the chance
who were interested in him.
HERNÁN REGUERA SERGIO'S AGENT
The coach at the time,
[Sergio] I would've been
It was a tough decision.
[indistinct chatter]
[Sergio] We were heading
and Khaldoon came to Los Angeles.
[indistinct chatter]
He told me, "You're not going anywhere."
He wanted to reassure me and promised
that if the same situation
he'd allow me to leave if I wanted to.
"Okay," I told him. "All right.
I'll stay another year
PEP GUARDIOLA
I didn't know about the meeting
That's the first thing. And second,
Gradually, he started to understand me
and I started to understand him, too.
[Pep] Sergio is "the legend,"
If you ask who embodies the success
there are many answers,
The goal that secured our first Premier
Am I going to argue with that?
and I hope it stays
On a day-to-day basis,
As a player, you want to be on the pitch.
[indistinct chatter]
[Sergio] Gabriel Jesus pressed opponents
And that made him unsure
Everyone wants to be loved in this life.
So, when I choose eleven players
those who aren't picked
It's about me not liking them.
[Sergio] At the beginning of the season,
I think Pep started to trust me, too.
[indistinct chatter]
[Sergio] He started using
Gabriel and I played together
[crowd cheering]
[Sergio] I assisted him against Liverpool.
[commentator in English]
And that is three-nil!
[crowd cheering]
[commentator] Agüero, so selfless there,
[in Spanish]
[indistinct chatter]
[Sergio] We were adopting a new play style
with some techniques
[indistinct chatter]
[Leo] Pep started asking
He stopped asking him to press so much,
because he wasn't…
[Sergio] If he was thinking
I was ready for it.
But that year, I wasn’t worried
that I could leave without any issues
[indistinct chatter]
[Sergio] I knew that it wouldn't be long
Honestly, it was meaningful because I knew
[crowd cheering]
[commentator in English]
-[crowd cheering]
The new outright top goal scorer
[crowd cheering]
2018 MANCHESTER
[Sergio in Spanish]
When he came to see me,
the first thing I thought about
MANCHESTER CITY VS. LEICESTER CITY
[commentator in English] Manchester City,
at the top of the Premier League.
As they take on 2016 champions,
[Sergio in Spanish]
in his room upstairs, not feeling well.
I knew he'd watch the match afterwards.
[commentator in English]
And finished off by Sergio Agüero
It matters little to him, though.
Kasper Schmeichel intercepted by Agüero!
Goal!
It's Agüero, Agüero lines up a shot.
And it's in from Sergio Agüero!
[chuckles] "He's definitely coming here.
I thought, "He'll come up here
He asked me, I can't remember what,
I said, "Yeah, yeah.
Good, you were really lucky
That's all," I said.
"Yeah, it was luck. Or are you trying
you knew you'd be scoring four goals?
It was luck." Every time I came over,
Yeah, yeah. No, well,
"You're a good player"
I've always said
I've ever known.
He's a star who behaves
Even the way he walks
I told him once or twice,
who are less important to the world,
yet they think they're much more important
-[indistinct chatter]
[Pep] For me, it's about helping me build
winning three or four Premier Leagues,
Pep sometimes
To help them play
That worked on me, for example,
because sometimes, I wanted
And it worked sometimes,
"I've already proven that I'm capable
and that I'm worthy
TWO YEARS BEFORE UNITED STATES
[crowd cheering]
[commentator]
"COPA AMÉRICA FINAL"
winning a Copa América or a World Cup.
The team has witnessed Chile win it twice,
Uruguay win it twice,
Argentina's dream of winning a tournament
After thinking about it a lot
I believe that that's it.
[interviewer] Are you quitting?
That's it. I fought hard. I tried.
and couldn't win them. I did my best.
Well, when Leo told me in the locker room
that he wouldn't be playing
it was very tough because I didn't know
I was like, "Just calm down.
And then, he goes and tells
[crowd cheering]
Once he calmed down,
2016 2021 BUENOS AIRES
It represented
as younger players were being
2021 BRAZIL COPA AMÉRICA
[Nicolás] Kun, Leo, Ángel, and I
[reporter] And it's time
They don't wear the jersey with pride.
They haven't achieved anything.
The journalists openly hated us.
on a football field
[indistinct chatter]
It was Leo's birthday that day.
He asked, "Who's going to host it?"
[indistinct chatter]
So, I helped him prepare the meat.
[laughs]
[interviewer] How did Sergio help out
-No. He didn't help with anything.
[Nicolás chuckling]
He jumps in
but he doesn't even try helping
[laughing] Yeah, he did help.
He just helped by watching the meat
-[indistinct chatter]
We're creating an explosion of flavor.
[Sergio] He didn't start the fire either.
I was the one
which is the most important part anyways.
We all made the barbecue,
and in Argentina,
[players singing] Happy birthday to you…
[Leo] Kun is kind of the mood maker
He's the one who promotes unity,
and tries to engage everyone,
gain confidence,
[indistinct chatter]
[Leo] He makes everything easier.
If he feels like doing something,
It's just who he is,
-[player] All right, all right.
[indistinct chatter]
[Sergio] Ultimately,
because chatting with us, the veterans,
was really helpful to the new guys,
By six or seven in the evening,
drinking mate, joking around,
[Leo] That Saturday
as we created something special
and strengthened
Everyone had the chance to speak,
and afterward,
And some people were starting to get
I'm telling you. Today, on June 10th,
And we, being the older ones, were like,
the younger guys were insisting,
We will win
-And we will go down in history.
The new guys
that maybe wasn't there before.
FINAL COPA AMÉRICA ARGENTINA VS. BRASIL
-[indistinct chatter]
[commentator] Ladies and gentlemen,
it's the Copa América final
Messi starts off. There he goes!
Make a wish, everyone.
A fantastic pass from De Paul to Di María.
Di María is off!
-[crowd cheering]
Goal…
for Argentina!
Twenty-eight years of waiting,
Thank you, Messi. Thank you, Scaloni.
Argentina is the champion once again.
[Nicolás] It took a long time,
There's no club title that compares
while wearing your country's colors.
[players singing]
♪ But this cup is Argentine ♪
[indistinct chatter]
6 MONTHS BEFORE MANCHESTER
[Sergio] There was a lot of buzz
[physician] All right. Again.
[Sergio] I was dealing with my knee issue,
I wanted to end my time in Europe
to stay ready for the World Cup.
[Sofía]
and he seemed really distressed about it.
Those were the times
He'd spent a decade of his life there.
[Sergio] Later that night,
Pep wasn't interested
It was difficult and hard to hear
because I didn't see that coming
[commentator in English] He's replaced
[crowd cheering]
[Sergio] Anything was possible with Pep
because he's a coach who doesn't hesitate
Pep wanted to talk with me…
He ended up telling me that he wouldn't be
and that it was difficult
"Are you going to say something?"
I could've said a lot,
since he'd already made his decision.
Then, he told me,
Then, I said that I'd keep training,
stay happy,
I remember specific training sessions
Or sometimes, he'd get mad at me
[indistinct chatter]
[Pep] I pushed him a lot, yelled at him,
And with some players, in the end, yes,
but I never had that feeling with Sergio.
We've had both good and bad conversations,
since everyone has to fight for their job.
-[crowd cheering]
We've won title after title,
I would say he's the best coach out there,
On the day I informed him
we did a small-sided practice session,
He proved just how wrong I was
He was going left and right,
I thought, "I really made a mistake
[in English] What's up, man?
[indistinct chatter]
MAY 23RD, 2021
[Sergio] Come on!
-[in English] The last one. You got this.
[in Spanish] In the match against Everton,
This is your game and your farewell.
[commentator in English]
for 16 City hat tricks.
For his sharpness, for his humility,
for his embrace of Manchester.
For being the man through
[stadium announcer] Sergio Agüero!
I looked like a model, huh?
[indistinct cheering]
I was feeling muscle pain in my adductor.
"Hey, just put me on
[commentator 1 in English]
Do you know what,
THANK YOU FOR EVERYTHING SERGIO
…if he didn't give Kun Agüero
[commentator 2 in English]
[commentator 1 in English]
It is Sergio Agüero!
Fairy tale farewell!
Fernandinho. Agüero!
It was a lucky day, just like my dad says.
WINNER - EUROPA LEAGUE - UEFA SUPER CUP
FA CUP - 7 ENGLISH LEAGUE CUPS
TOP FOREIGN SCORERS PREMIER LEAGUE
01 SERGIO AGÜERO - 184 GOALS
03 MOHAMED SALAH - 153 GOALS
05 JIMMY FLOYD - 127 GOALS
MOST HAT-TRICKS SCORED - PREMIER LEAGUE
02 ALAN SHEARER - 11
04 THIERRY HENRY - 8
[cheering, indistinct chatter]
There are things you can't train for…
RODRIGO HERNÁNDEZ
…and Sergio was clearly born
[indistinct chatter, cheering]
It was a beautiful farewell,
of an amazing career, right?
The speech Sergio gave
In crucial moments,
these things could happen, right?
He sounds like he's just talking
[in English] Thanks for Khaldoon,
all the staff, and my teammates,
[in Spanish] How do you say?
[in English] Uh… for the--
[in Spanish] The… You know.
[in English] You know.
-Yeah, the staff.
[Pep in Spanish]
and I think he has a really good heart.
by the way he looks,
and the way he interacts with others,
[stadium announcer in English]
thank Sergio Agüero!
He is a special person for all that.
We cannot replace him, we cannot.
[♪ sentimental music playing]
[♪ music concludes]
[♪ tense music playing]
15TH DECEMBER 2021
[in Spanish] I felt really calm.
Until that moment came for me
I'd already been processing the situation.
I wouldn't play
I took it pretty well, very calmly.
[indistinct chatter]
[Adriana]
"Mom, I need to go to a press conference."
Sergio hadn't gotten any clothes ready,
so I was ironing a shirt
He said, "No, I'm completely fine."
[indistinct chatter]
[Adriana] I had no idea what would happen
everything that was on his mind.
[Gerard] Having to abruptly say goodbye
which was your whole life.
Getting up every morning,
playing games every three days,
that sense of security that helped you
or 90 thousand people is no longer there.
It's not my best angle, but hey,
That one suits you better, all right?
Hey!
[sobs]
[announcer] I request the presence
and also the president of F.C. Barcelona,
[crowd applauds]
[indistinct chatter]
[exhales] So, um,
is to announce that…
well, I've…
football.
-[♪ somber music playing]
[sighs] Oh! God fucking dammit.
[exhales, cries, sniffs]
So, I've made the decision to retire
[sniffs]
but, anyway, I'm genuinely happy
He was looking at the crowd, everywhere.
I never asked him,
that he was waiting for his father
But he didn't go to the farewell
I think my son always hoped for that.
And I think he didn't lose hope
[breathes deeply]
[Leonel]
Uh, I watched it later on…
on the news.
No, no, no, no, I didn't want to see it.
And if he was looking for me,
Before he did the interview
that he was going to quit football,
I called him and said,
I told him,
"I never saw a player
[Sergio] And yeah,
and I remember that I'd answered him,
[chuckles] "I mean, you waited
[crowd cheering]
[Sergio] I was kind of sad,
He finally told me something…
6 MONTHS LATER
MANCHESTER
[Sofía]
He wasn't really enjoying
Maybe his mind was always
But now, I think he's more in
He's enjoying life
-Okay, should we… go see the statue?
MANCHESTER CITY HONORS SERGIO
[indistinct chatter]
[cheering]
SERGIO AGÜERO BELOVED STRIKER
For Sergio, it was a very special moment
and see his statue.
[indistinct chatter]
[Hernán]
The number of goals he scored,
The titles they won with City
Sergio! Sergio! Sergio!
[indistinct chatter]
[in English] The most iconic moment
-For the Premier League.
And then… No, no, it like a question.
-[person 1] Oh, question. Right, okay.
-[person 1 laughs]
-[♪ epic music playing]
[presenter 1 in English]
Sergio Agüero!
[cheering]
[Julián] That last-minute goal to win the
but…
[crowd] Sergio! Sergio! Sergio!
…I've watched a video of all the goals
JULIÁN ÁLVAREZ
…every one of them is incredible.
[cheering]
Beyond all that,
what stuck with me the most is
A truly amazing human being
That's what leaves
Hey, dude! What's up with your heart, man?
YAYA TOURÉ MANCHESTER CITY PLAYER
[staff member] Agüero!
With Guardiola, the bond of care
now that they're no longer player
-Hey. Everything good?
You're looking good!
[indistinct chatter]
6 MONTHS AFTER QATAR
[Sergio] My experience
I'd been to three World Cups as a player,
but being on the other side
Hey, guys! We're in Qatar.
[in English] But you don't like Messi?
-Not really.
[in Spanish] They don't like Messi?
Come on. Let's get outta here.
I got a small bag and some other things.
-[Maurico] Napkins.
Yes. Oh, should I get more?
[Mauricio]
Spent all day at home.
Kicked the ball around occasionally.
I had a few Argentine friends there.
MAURICIO DEL CASTILLO
"Sounds good. Who are you going with?"
I showed up with my brother. [laughs]
-[family member 1] What are you doing?
-He can't go any faster.
I played football yesterday,
[indistinct chatter]
[Mauricio] He missed the World Cup
However, he was involved
chatting with the boys around the clock.
Sergio was always there, you know?
It's about not pushing him away,
but letting him be involved instead,
I understood what they were going through
so I know when to reach out or drop by.
[Leo] It was lucky that he could explore
and somewhat forget about football,
but it hit him hard because of the way
Because he was always an important
and it was hard not to have him with us.
[cheering]
We always tried to include him
and to make him feel like
[cheering]
Benja is quite… It's the first time
-With the national team, right?
Yeah, it was with the national team
-If you noticed, at the World Cup… I was…
I wasn't a player anymore, so to speak.
It was hard for me to accept that.
BENJAMÍN AGÜERO
But I'd already accepted the fact
from basically the beginning.
That was hard for me,
but I enjoyed watching
For a while, he completely stopped…
I… I was really worried
because I thought it'd cause him
but he ended up enjoying it a lot.
[cheering]
[Benjamín] The goal
was probably the one against Mexico, yeah.
-Leo's goal. The first one. Yeah.
Listen, wh-- where are you? In your room?
We're in our room right now.
-In our room?
But you never invited me
-[player] We took the room over, Kun.
No, that's right, you… you told me.
When he said "in our room,"
"Oh, right, ours."
After I stopped sharing a room with him
-and no longer…
…played for the national team,
Because… I don't know, honestly.
I should… should just stay there alone.
Hey, thanks. Uh, good luck,
And like I said the other day,
you guys are truly amazing.
Well, thanks, man.
We miss you. You and Gio.
You know we're always…
He's someone I deeply care about,
a friend who's given me football memories
and he's a very loyal, sensitive,
truly a great friend to his friends.
[commentator]
2022 QATAR WORLD CUP FINAL
[commentator] The World Cup final in Qatar
If he scores, Argentina wins.
It's the final penalty
the ones who started playing
around neighborhoods, on the streets,
And that's Montiel. We are all Montiel.
[cheering]
[commentator] Goal! Goal!
Argentina! Goal!
We are all champions!
FIFA WORLD CUP QATAR 2022
[commentator]
[Nicolás] For us, he never left.
We talk constantly,
just bothering each other.
He never left. He was never really gone
[Sergio] I was happy because
my former teammates, and friends.
Especially for Leo, who really
I was really happy for him and for the
It doesn't matter. Even though I didn't
[chuckles]
-Three, two. Right there!
Yeah?
Three, three.
[♪ soft music playing]
[♪ theme music playing]
[♪ theme music concludes]