DAVO: Suárez just came out, tell him, the Uruguayan "truco" (card game) is shit
I mean, its so difficult to understood
RAFA: The Argentine "truco" is like the Uruguayan "truco" but for children.
No, seriously I'm telling you, it's the Uruguayan "truco"
for children. when you are
small and you can't understand how to play
Uruguayan "truco", they teach you the Argentine "truco"
COBRA: But which came first, Rafa?
DAVO: I like the Uruguayan "truco" the same, Rafa.
Rafa, sorry, sorry. Suárez just left
take a second to look for something to drink.
and he just said that the Uruguayan "truco" is a bullshit.
Luis appeared and just said
which is very good. Did you hear it?
RAFA: Yes. Because he's a drag...
DAVO: You're a stupid snitch!
COBRA: Suck-up. average suck-up.
He's a mean sucker.
DAVO: And you are a stupid snitch.
COBRA: No, idiot. But I tell it like it is.
RAFA: Do you know what we have to do Luis?
You and I against Davo and Cobra.
Or the Davo and the Cobra choose one
and you tell your partner, you have to tell him two things,
enter streaming now
and play a "truco" game,
Uruguay - Argentina
and we played a Uruguayan-style game
and an Argentine-style match.
SUAREZ: No, but the Uruguayan needs time, idiot
to learn
RAFA: well, let them handle themselves. Look how crazy they are,
Hey? Davo streams 4 hours a day
and gets up at 5 in the afternoon
and the other one you have in the next room
Practice for an hour and a half. It's not that hard either
in construction, huh?
SUAREZ: Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
MESSI: What are you talking about? Of me?
RAFA: Look.
Yes of course
that you're on the go all day.
You have to learn to play the Uruguayan "truco"
MESSI: What happened?
Good morning, people.
COBRA: What are you doing, Leo? How are you?
DAVO: How are you doing?
MESSI: What's wrong, Cobra? Davo, is everything okay?
COBRA: Everything calm.
DAVO: Here watching the game. 2-0 25 minutes.
He scored two goals in 8 minutes, high pressure
and now the match was evened out a little more.
COBRA: Analyze Davo, analyze
MESSI: Yes, I saw that he was winning 2-0
RAFA: but analyze and comment on the game now!
I was just barding with "truco" and fucking around
that the Uruguayan "truco" was shit...
COBRA: Goal!!!
DAVO: Goal de Deportivo LSM!   3 to 0
MESSI: I just arrived, look.
SUAREZ: Was it a goal? Yes, yes
COBRA: Good definition. Yes. Yes,
3 - 0.
SUAREZ: Ah! They think as if they were...
good as a forward. Hey, "Nine"?
COBRA: Thank you, Luis. Thank you. Thanks a lot.
MESSI: Were they talking about "truco"?
SUAREZ: they were saying which one was better,
asking to see.
MESSI: No, , the Uruguayan "truco", I  don't understand it.
I had played a couple of times, but
COBRA: Say something, Rafa. Now let's see, say something.
MESSI: No, I don't know but I don't understand it
RAFA: You can learn it. Look, it's not a kidney transplant.
You spend 15 minutes concentrating
if they are on the go all day.
15 minutes...
MESSI: Nah well, but I saw him play a little bit there and
It's very different, very different.
DAVO: Let there be a card that has more
value that Ace of spades takes away a lot of credibility.
COBRA: "Espadilla." "Espadilla", friend. Speak well.
RAFA: The ace. "spades ace"? What is spades ace?
Its called "Espadilla" and "bastillo".
[Laughs]
SUAREZ: Listen Davo, you were speechless. Look how you can talk,
Hey? You can speak as you have been speaking,
Hey? Because you are...
RAFA: He's terrified, he's terrified
COBRA: No, no, Davo didn't say what you thought about "mate" (traditional argentinian drink).
now that Leo is there
DAVO: I love it! It is my favorite drink.
SUAREZ: He says he doesn't trust those who drink mate
MESSI: Why?
DAVO: I don't know, I never really liked mate, to be honest.
SUAREZ: That's what the Cobra said.
COBRA: No, no, he didn't say that. He didn't say that.
MESSI: No, but the Cobra drinks mate, yes I saw him drinking.
RAFA: You being athletes...
Davo has healthy habits.
Tell him, Davo, tell him what time you get up
and what you eat during the day.
DAVO: Two, three in the afternoon I start
and I go to bed type 6 -7 am.
But why, but because I stream all night.
MESSI: Sure. It happens
When you started you didn't sleep at all
COBRA: yes...
DAVO: Exactly, during the day there are always matches,
You cannot stream during the day.
The key is at night
that everything is over.
RAFA: And what do you eat? For example, you wake up and what, protein?
fiber? fruit?
DAVO: What a goal!
COBRA: 4 to 0
SUAREZ: No! Nine again! mother fucker.
*the 9th had a goal bonus for every goal he scored*
RAFA: Leo... open the wallet.
SUAREZ: Let's send a message to the Coach
to take him out.
COBRA: No! Leave it, Luis, leave it.
MESSI: Davo, you always started
from the beginning, you started with
Boca Juniors streams and football?
DAVO: Yes, yes, yes. From the beginning.
MESSI: Since you started?
Yes, in fact also at that time, already in 2020
that I started analizing football - Boca juniors at night,
So I adapted a little to the schedule
which I could stream and that was it, done.
I mean, I never changed the content.
always the same basically
MESSI: Are you a Madrid fan too, Davo?
COBRA: Ow, ow, ow.
DAVO: "too"? Who else here would be a Real Madrid fan?
not Cobrita ...
MESSI: Not because you are a Boca fan... We are talking about Boca
So I say, are you also a Madrid fan?
DAVO: Ah! uh, no, no. Not a "Madrid FAN"
But I have a colleague who is
a huge Barça fan and I like to mess with him...
I like to mess with him when i can...
MESSI: Ah, that's why ...
DAVO: Yes, Leo, yes, please.
RAFA: You sleazebag! How scared he is!...
He's terrified.
SUAREZ: Listen , so, show us, there behind your...
DAVO: Two Argentines, two Boca Juniors fan...
RAFA: Yeah! back back what do you have back there?...
DAVO: We have to compete in something...
SUAREZ: Behind you... behind, where is Leo's back there?  Let's see,
Move the camera a little...
DAVO: There...
there is Román's and Diego's... and Messi's...
It is the one from the 2010 South Africa World Cup
SUAREZ: No, the picture, I mean, the picture of Leo. Where is it?
With was back there...
DAVO: Oh, it happens that the one who made the mural only made Maradona.
SUAREZ: Oh, but didn't you have Leo's picture in the other house?
a picture?
DAVO: Yes, obviously. I had Leo first, then Román
and in fact I always covered Diego.
Leo was always seen alone...
Now I put Diego there.
SUAREZ: Yes, yes, yes, yes. That's why.
I was serious. I thought you had Leo's
with the cup
DAVO: No, I had that for two years in my previous setup.
He was always first.
COBRA: Davo speak Spanish, please.
"Setup"? Remember that they are footballers. "Setup"?
"Setup", friend? Room.
DAVO: My streaming room. My work room.
COBRA: "My study place"
RAFA: Let's see yours, Cobra?
SUAREZ: He says hes a terrible striker...
MESSI: Oh Yes?
COBRA:  I always had everything the same here.
The only thing i did...
I put new pictures over time.
Look, let's see if we see something there.
first I had Leo's with the Copa América.
There is Diego, the awards.
Well, then Leo is back there too...
It's a little awkward, because Leo is listening right now
it's a little uncomfortable,
but hey, I have everything here
literally, that is, everything that has happened
I was basically adding another picture
COBRA: Like this... Here is the picture with Leo in Miami...
SUAREZ: And you, Rafa, don't show that you rented a guesthouse to join
RAFA: I am imprisoned, I am imprisoned.
Look, there's my partner.
Yes, I have nothing. I'm in a pension, bad.
Look...here I am.
There's nothing, I'm not really at home.
COBRA: Good wall huh,
nice wall color, huh?
SUAREZ: Nah, he's out, he's out... Let's thank Rafa
who left with his daughters and is there
putting all the good vibes on it.
RAFA: What is the worst defeat in Boca Juniors history?
Davo? in lost matches
SUAREZ: He's not listening...it happens...
Rafa, we were talking, Rafa,
you are kind of old
You're old for these streams and all that.
You have to understand when they speak, do you understand?
MESSI: What did you ask him?
RAFA: I'm outta here, I'm outta here... Ok, I'm outta here
SUAREZ: What did you ask, Rafa?
RAFA: No, because Boca now is losing 4 to 0...
When did they lose by a bigger margin?
Davo knows all the statistics,
the matches.
DAVO: We once lost 4 to 0 in 2005 with Chivas
in Libertadores Cup. Hard defeat.
COBRA: And also with a local team San Juan it wasn't 6-1? I believe.
DAVO: It's true. In 2013 we lost 6-1
with San Martín de San Juan.
DAVO: Leo, I have a question for you.
How do you drink "mate"? however it comes?...
MESSI: stop, stop, stop.
What are you going to ask?
Don't start asking, huh.
DAVO: No, no, " mate "!
MESSI: We're watching the game, eh?
RAFA: Leo shoots! Leo shoots! I love you that way, spicy.
MESSI: Don't start it! don't start it!
[Laughs]
MESSI: From the game? What?
DAVO: Yes, yes, yes. I was going to ask you what you think about the goal.
who just scored
COBRA: Hey! He didn't ask that!
MESSI: What? What happened?
DAVO: No, no. How do you drink "mate" , that was...
Sweet? bitter? as it comes...
MESSI: Bitter, bitter.
At first I drank it... when I was a kid I drank it sweet,
my mom drank it sweet
and then when I started to become alone,
I started to drink it bitter.
Actually I was making it sweet and I started to drink it bitter
because of the sugar issue
and I started to drink it bitter and it stayed like that.
Also in Nationals team i drinked it bitter.
RAFA: And you use Uruguayan herbs? or you drink it with argentinian herbs?...
...which is firewood
COBRA: Firewood?
MESSI: No, when I was in Rosario...
however it comes, when I was a kid. Later on...
RAFA: Now I'm not telling you,
I'm not asking you to say brands, I'm asking you,
Do you drink with Uruguayan herbs noww?
MESSI: yes... Uruguayan
RAFA: with real uruguayean herbs or you drink it with firewood with warm water argentinian way?
MESSI: Now with the Uruguayan
RAFA: Look...
COBRA: You allways want to impose something, right?
Rafa? all the time, Uruguayan "truco" ...
Uruguayan games... Uruguayan "mate".
RAFA: I am simply exposing a reality,
an information.
COBRA: Ah, okay...
RAFA: He drinks with Uruguayan herbs because its better!
COBRA: We don't know, he likes it better.
MESSI: Yes, it depends for whom.
Of course
COBRA: sure.
SUAREZ: And you Cobra?
COBRA: Eh, no, I have here
the one my mother gave me, I don't know,
It's not spacial. I don't want to say the brand
so that we avoid brands, but it is a...
supposedly one that makes me lose weight,
but I don't think its working.
RAFA: You have to eat it, you idiot!
MESSI: I saw you sometimes...
MESSI: I saw your "mates".
You prepare really bad ones, washed.
COBRA: No, stop, Leo. But well, it's just that
my "mates" washes off,
but I can't get up from the stream, you see?
Of course.
COBRA: It's complicated for me...
MESSI: You make it last all day, of course
COBRA: Sure, ... although sometimes im with the same "mate"
And i recharge like 3 thermos...
MESSI: Sure.
SUAREZ: No, you can't, idiot!
For that, make yourself a tea.
COBRA:but the problem is that I have to get up,
and it hurts my knee
get up very often... kindding
It's because I have to go down and it looks bad to leave the screen.
That's why, seriously.
Before I also drank sweet mate, then I switched to...
I became a real man and now drink it the normal way
MESSI: Well, but inland there are many people who drink it sweet.
COBRA: Yes, that's right.
DAVO: And some of them also add sweetener too.
MESSI: Yes.
RAFA: Well...
MESSI: with Kun Aguero in Copa América
2015 in Chile,
I don't know why Kun...
It occurred to him to put honey in it.
DAVO: No!
RAFA: Seriosly?...
MESSI: I drank mate with honey.
MESSI: He put honey in the water
RAFA: IN the water?
COBRA: And you liked it?
MESSI: It was sweet, it was good I guess, we drank it.
COBRA: Yes, my grandmother used to make it with honey for me at one point,
Literally, my grandmother, too...
It is a rather strange custom.
SUAREZ: I had never heard of mate with honey
MESSI: He put honey into the water...
We drank it like that the entire Copa América ...
in Chile.
COBRA: That thing, Rafa, is very Argentine, eh? Because
You might want to claim that for yourself too...
RAFA: What? drinking mate with honey? Yeah,
It's yours. No, no, no. You keep it,
stay calm. We may drink it with some other herbs
It could be... Of course! but that's all yours
honey, sugar and sweetener,
especially the sweetener, adding sweetener
to mate is very Argentinian, yes.
COBRA: Okay... So Dulce leche, where is it from, Rafa?
RAFA: Dulce de leche is Uruguayan, there is no discussion.
It's like Gardel, There's no doubt about that.
COBRA: Did you know, Leo, that I played recently?
a game at Inter Miami and they kicked me?
MESSI: Where? when you come here?
COBRA: Yes, when I went to see you...
We played a game of content creators
at Inter Miami and they kicked me out
I mean, in the semi-finals I scored two goals
and in the final they kicked me out for hitting other player.
MESSI: Oh but you played like a tournament?
COBRA: Yes, yes, yes.
MESSI: Really?
COBRA: Yes, yes. They kicked me out. Wrong decision from the ref.
SUAREZ: But it was one of...?
Was it now in September?
COBRA: no, no... it was...
in the club world cup, nine
DAVO: You can see the picture of him, all dressed like Inter Miami,
and the referee sending him off
making the elbow gesture.
RAFA: Yes, I saw photos and it was wrong because
Someone said: "it looks like Peppa Pig" and i don't agree...
COBRA: No, that has nothing to do with it...
MESSI: Eeey dude
RAFA: Because it's not good to talk about bodies...
COBRA: No, no, no. Oh ok. Well, but
Physical appearance doesn't matter here, playing football matters here...
Everyone does what they can.
RAFA: Sure.
COBRA: That's why...
SUAREZ: Tell him, Cobra, tell Leo how you describe yourself
How yo characterized... you characterize yourself as a striker
COBRA: Yes...
Hey, hey, good hit... good first touch,
good return, good feint,
speed, explosive, fast,
good definition, eh, I have a good free kick,
Honestly, I'm not going to lie to you. ,
Penalties i take charge, it depends which penalty.
And corner kick if they force me to shoot it. And good aerial game.
MESSI: How?... How come "i take charge depending on which penalty"?
COBRA: Sure, I mean, if it's 5 to 0   I'll kick it.
If it is a final I prefer someone else to kick it.
I mean, it depends on the match
It depends on the match...
Okeey...
MESSI: Did you lose in semifinals?
COBRA: No, no, we reached the final
and we lost the final. There they sent me off and played
all matches with one less player.
No, really, I felt really bad.
MESSI: So someone else coudn't play, you had to play with one less player?
COBRA: Sure, we were one player short.
I felt really bad afterwards because
They were all looking at me with a strange face,
"Hey, dude you screwed up" and well, nothing,
I felt bad, but... nothing
my head went away...
SUAREZ: Do you have a team of streamers?
of players?
COBRA: There is an Argentine selection of streamers,
correct. Hey...
DAVO: But no, it wasn't that one he was sent off.
it was one organized by Inter Miami.
SUAREZ: No, no, no. Yes, I know, but now
are you in the streamers team?
DAVO: Oh. We are not. No...
COBRA: No, we aren't.
SUAREZ: They didn't call you?
RAFA: They were not called.
DAVO: They don't call us! Kidding. But...
There are very good players, there is a high level.
SUAREZ: Yes?
COBRA: Yes, but now with Davo we are going to travel
to Spain to play a match
to play against Spain
SUAREZ: But with the Argentinian team?
COBRA: Latin American, Latin America against Spain
DAVO: It's Latin America against Spain at the Málaga stadium
its now, at the end of the month, and Cobra doesn't stop texting me,
I swear, once a day he writes to me
and he tells me, "Listen to me, Davito, if I run
and you have the ball, you have to give it to me,
I'll put it in," he tells me. Like this every two...
He writes to me once a day, like if...
I tell him, "We are only gonna play for 10 minutes,
We are both horrible." He tells me,
"If I run, just give it to me."
I give it to you. But what are you going to do?
COBRA: Well...
MESSI: What position do you play, Davo?
SUAREZ: He didn't listen...
COBRA: What kind of player are you, Davito? Leo asked you.
DAVO: And I'm more like you, Leo. I am a 10,
Just as I respect that the Cobra is nine,
I like to play more like a 10 ,
I like to take charge of free kicks,
I also really like to have
always the ball with me, I don't like
to lose it, I have it,
If i pass it a long pass has to be a precise one,
I like short passes, strikes,
I have good first touch, definition too.
MESSI: Riquelme style, Riquelme style, like your idol
DAVO: Exactly. Yes
to control the game in my own time.
To have the ball and the game
It's going to be played the way I want. I'm not going to wait
Let others tell me how to play it.
SUAREZ: AJAJAJA
DAVO: I'm more of that style myself.
MESSI: You control the game.
DAVO: Yesss totally.
Yes, I am similar to Riquelme
SUAREZ: Listen so in a team...
You two get along well, you get along great.
If Cobra plays... if Cobra he's "the nine"
and he plays like me, and you play like Leo...
COBRA: Yes...the thing is we play like that in Play Station,
not in real life
SUAREZ: Rafa, orginice a match,
orginice a match with this two
RAFA: You are making me mad!
We have to make a challenge.
We play, but whenever they want
because apart from what I saw, they are both sinister,
They are horrible...
SUAREZ: What?
RAFA: We have a commercial break...
SUAREZ: Ok.
RAFA: Perfect.
SUAREZ: We'll see you later. Give it a hug.
COBRA: Of course, that's what happens, friend.
I think and say, "What would have...
Sometimes don't you Davito  get up
and say, "What would have happened if
I dedicated myself to being a football player?
How far would you have gotten?" Don't you think?
DAVO: Being honest?...
COBRA: Yes...
DAVO: I think that i would be nominee... a Ballon d'Or nominee...
COBRA: Really?
DAVO: I'm not telling you i would have won it.
COBRA: Stop. You or me?
DAVO: Me... I'm not telling you i've had won it because...
It's just the Messi era, we're talking about
another level, but in another era, i could have won it
COBRA: And a golden boot? You think I could have won it?
Davito?
DAVO: Yes! you would have won it. The issue is that also,
it was the Messi  / Suárez era, difficult to with the golden boot.
Complicated.
COBRA: Well, but maybe one, I don't know,
I don't know.
RAFA: We have visitors!
COBRA: There is someone hidden there that we don't see.
RAFA: Dude... don't you have any more cell phones?
Do you have only one cell phone? so you dont look cramped
in just one frame
SUAREZ: What thing?
Why?
RAFA: No, because if you put more than one cell phone,
You'll look good. You look cramped there.
I can see two people and
a pink shirt there, I don't know.
SUAREZ: He's reading.
RAFA: Oh, he's a reader.
RAFA: "Diosito"!
DAVO: How are you doing Rodri?
COBRA: How you doing, Rodri? How are you?
DE PAUL: But dude, this started really early.
I just woke up...
COBRA: It's like that...
DE PAUL: Between Cobra and Davo...
I was just listening...
Saying "We" "we"... it's your first game!
First time watching the team, idiots. What are saying?
DAVO: No! No!
DE PAUL: "We have to score more goals,"
"it works for us, we have to classify",
"We"?
COBRA: Well, we're part of the team. Let's see,
DAVO: We are here, you see, we are part of it, aren't we, Luis?
SUAREZ: Eeeh, yes. Well...
DE PAUL: Are these two reinforcements already?
Rafa is already in. I know he is...
COBRA: Well...
RAFA: They have to let up on the "reinforcements"!
* Uruguayan sandwich *
[Laughs]
DE PAUL: Are you physically ok? can you...
Are you up for playing a little bit?...
DAVO: I'm in
RAFA: Cobra says he's in
DAVO: I support like 15 minutes.
DE PAUL: You won a prize yesterday, didn't you, Davo?
Congratulations.
DAVO: Yes, yes.
DE PAUL: You won a prize, right?
DAVO: Yesterday. Yesterday, a streamer award
in Idol Awards
DE PAUL: For what?
DAVO: Coverage for best streamer i won...
DE PAUL: You don't look so happy, dude.
MESSI: Yes, he's saying it like "yeah meh".
[Laughs]
RAFA: He's still half awake.
COBRA: It's okay if you smile, friend.
RAFA: He don't even... He don't even knows if he is happy or sad
He is still groggy. He doesn't even know where he is right now.
It's the first time he is streaming at 10 in the morning
DE PAUL: You don't care at all!
DAVO: No, no! I swear It's not like that .
The thing is,it makes me a little embarrassed
I guess.
eh...
DE PAUL: You shoudn't, we saw you
DAVO: Yes you are right...
MESSI: And you, Cobra, you didn't win anything?
COBRA: No, no, they didn't even nominate me to say hello,
but well, unfortunately
You have to keep working. It's like that.
MESSI: What happened, you weren't even nominated?
COBRA: No, no, literally I was not nominated for anything
but I was chill, it doesn't matter
DE PAUL: They're shutting you down, Cobra.
COBRA: It's difficult, it's difficult, but
It was not my time, it was not my time. But the thing
that hurt me the most is that generally
in those
In those events what hurts me is that
generally there is good food catering
And I wanted to go to eat something,
but not even that, so it was complicated
DE PAUL: No way...
MESSI: But not even a nomination?
Dude
DE PAUL: Not even nominated?
COBRA: Hey, life is hard
RAFA: They're blaming you a little, it seems to me Cobra.
COBRA: No, no, it's ok. No problem,
no problem. It's like that.
DAVO: No, no. For me, it was wrong.
In fact, I told the event organizer,
Not having Cobra ...
It was a shame, and they said "yes, but hey, thing are like that..."
DE PAUL: Yes, yes, "I told them, I told them"
and when you were up there
when you received the award, that's when you had to say it stupid!
Don't believe him Cobra !
DAVO: I regretted it Cobrita, sorry
DE PAUL: He didn't put his heart out for you!
DAVO: Sorry Cobrita, sorry. What do you want?
I had my mom there crying and you spect me to say:
"Cobra should to be here"?
Let Cobra suck my balls. Thats it.
COBRA: No! stop it!
It's okay, it's okay. Davo, you'll see...
when you say I need a video for YouTube...
I'm going to tell you "I can't friend, I can't"
RAFA: Question for everyone except Davo...
Isn't it stupid?...
"Yes, this is for Mile who is my love,
who is always there for me... who accompanies me"
instead of friends, who are always there.
MESSI: Nah, it's okay dude...
MESSI: We just saw the speech, for me it was good
RAFA: You are a henpecked husband too, you and Luis...
Well...you can't talk
Of course
COBRA: no, but it's ok, nothing happens.
It's like that, Rafa, when I have to upload some
video he' will have to ask Mile to make it
RAFA: Sure.
COBRA: It's okay.
SUAREZ: But he also thanked his mother
RAFA: In three months she realizes, she leaves him,
She dumps him, she dumps him...
DAVO: Stop, stop, I have to interrupt you there, howcome
"she leaves him""? what do you mean by that?
RAFA: Sure, sooner or later he will leave you
RAFA: sooner or later she's going to leave you, and you're going to go crying with
Cobra, which will receive you half naked
with two boxes of pizza and he's going to tell you "come here friend"
Is allright...
DE PAUL: but it doesn't matter, it doesn't matter what's going to happen!
he felt it, you have to do what
you feels...
no matter what comes!
DAVO: Listen to the ones who know, Rafa, so much so that
you talk, listen the ones who know. Apart from that its true
she support me every day, how can I not recognize her?
DE PAUL: You only never felt grateful for ...
You never felt grateful for Cobra, because you didn't say it,
but you felt the other thing.
DAVO: Exactly. I thought about Cobra,
but I don't know, it didn't come out.
After the awards...
we went partying after the awards... here Cobrix...
COBRA: Nono, I didn't go out. I went to take care of you,
I went to take care of you, it's different.
RAFA: And you stayed up all night?
COBRA: And, sadly yes. But it's okey.
MESSI: Oh! well but you look good...
COBRA: Working hard Leo, working as always
SUAREZ: You're looking forward to the match to end, right?
NO PAUL: You don't know if you're with the green players or the white ones, right?
The ones that have to win...
You just shout the goals
DAVO: Enjoying youth...
COBRA: Well...
NO PAUL: Cobra is the one that uses
three thermoses when drinkin mate?
MESSI: Yes, Cobra
SUAREZ: "Nine", "el nine"
He likes to be called "el nine"
DAVO: No Luchito don't! Luchito no... "Cobra" it's fine
COBRA: Thank you, thank you Luis.
How did you call me Rodri? I didn't hear well Rodri...How did you call me?
FROM PAUL: Nine, ¿nine?
COBRA: Yes, yes, yes. Rodri, I hear you
DE PAUL: Three thermoses not changing the herbs?
MESSI: Davo doesn't drink mate, Davo doesn't like it.
COBRA: Of course,  I already know that
It's a little watery, but that's it
I can't replace the herbs, you see? I have to go down,
change it... in the middle of the stream...
it gets complicated
DE PAUL: But you handle it well, let's say.
COBRA: I 'm okay . I 'm okay with that.
I try to handle it . Yes, yes, yes.
DE PAUL: And Davito no  mate at all?
DAVO: No, no, I'm not used to drink mate, I don't have the habit.
I am more of a water person
as it comes.
DE PAUL: No, here th "mate"... here making "mate"
What can i say, it depends on the day,
the humor, like you see
DAVO: But you drink every day don't you?
DE PAUL: These two are gettin old, you know?
It's not easy for me, with the years
you have less patience.
RAFA: They get crafty, don't they, Rodri?
DE PAUL: That's the word, they both get crafty...
getting closer to 40... they're close to 40 already
DAVO: Listen Rodri, I have to tell you something.
In yesterday's awards, "pollo" Alvarez
won an award for best... viral clip
of the year, and its your clip,
where you rate your clothes.
COBRA: Correct.
DE PAUL: If its not for me "pollo" can't win anything Davo .
It has to be something like that...
DAVO: He thanked you, there were literally 800 clips and won:
"De Paul with "pollo" Alvarez clip"
winning prize"
DE PAUL: How strange, I didn't even know that.
DAVO: They should have told you...
DE PAUL: But you don't get money, you only win the prize, don't you?
DAVO: It's the prize. It's just the prize...
DE PAUL: Let "pollo" keep it then...
RAFA: And Cobra wich one won?
DAVO: Eh...No, they didn't nominate him.
DE PAUL: "Making "mates"...
"the one who lasts the longest with the same herbs" of the year
COBRA: Motivational speech
SUAREZ: The one who uses the most water...
COBRA: No... Well, it's difficult. Well, but let's see,
I ask you a question, Luis.
I have a question, Luis.
MESSI: But... Have you ever won Cobra or not?
Its not the first year that they give them...
COBRA: Yes, last year... last year I won
not the same awards,
but I did win other prizes.
DE PAUL: You won the love of the people, Cobrita!
That's what's worth the most
COBRA: Lets go, Rodri.
DAVO: Thats right! The streets don't forget Cobrita!
COBRA: Lets go, Rodri. I mean...
I don't want to compare myself, but for example Suárez
He was not always nominated for the Ballon d'Or, for example.
DAVO: No, no, no...
DE PAUL: Well, but you're comparing yourself. You say
"I don't want to compare myself" but you are comparing yourself.
COBRA: Well, well, I mean, I want to talk
a bit of football history,
That's what I mean, you understand? For example...
and it's not that strange.
DE PAUL: And he (Messi) didn't win nine Ballon d'Or either,
so...
COBRA: Sure, i guess. Well...
DE PAUL: He didn't win nine Ballon d'Or, it's the same.
DAVO: Okay but anyway, stop, let's not underestimate ourselves...
In this call there are eight Ballon d'Ors.
Why throw us down
among us?
RAFA: Just stay you three
And there are still eight.
DAVO: No no, Cobrita has one too back there
COBRA: Sure, it's true. I have it back there
DE PAUL: Stop... is there an award? for...
for streaming,
similar to Ballon d'Or in football. Are there any?
COBRA: Theoretically it is this...
DAVO: The streamer of the year award
RAFA: Oh, look how he is dressed...
DE PAUL: Streamer of the year?
DAVO: Exactly.
DE PAUL: Is that it?
DAVO: Its that...
COBRA: No, not if you're laughing at me, ok?
Don't laugh, Rodri because I'm leaving.
You are disrespecting my work.
DE PAUL: Are you crazy? I mean...
SUAREZ: A cucumber? What is it? a leek?
COBRA: No, no, you're laughing!
No, I feel bad, I feel bad.
DE PAUL: I seriously ask, which one is that?
the streamer of the year?
DAVO: Yes, yes, the streamer of the year.
COBRA: Yes. Something like that
DAVO: Cobra won the last... The last edition
The one he has its the real one. And every year it is returned
COBRA: And Davo won it last month.
Davo won it last month.
DAVO: No idiot, last year...
COBRA: It's like when, for example,
Modric gave the golden ball to Leo.
Yes, that's what I say, the last prize.
It's like when Modric gave the
golden ball to Leo...
So, it's the same. It's the same.
DAVO: Because that is the original award,
once a year it changes.
DE PAUL: And you both won it?
Davo this year and Cobra last year?
Davo: No, no. Me in 2023 and him in 2024.
Me first, Rodri.
DE PAUL: Ok...
COBRA: Hey, what's wrong with you? Enlarged
DE PAUL: This guy is an idiot Cobra, he's a pisser, he's a pisser.
MESSI: And this year, when do they do them?
COBRA: like... we don't know. I imagine that
in December
We hope in December.
COBRA: But if they dont continue
I'll keep it Leo, what do you think?
DAVO: The Martín Fierro awards are also in December
that we are both going.
COBRA: Sure.
DE PAUL: Yes. Martín Fierro there was a lot of drama,
A lot of controversy.
DAVO: Yes! Now the digital awards are coming...
DE PAUL: You see? We are aware of everything
DAVO: How do you say I should be dressed? Rodri?
to the Martín Fierro awards...
Suit? Or do I play it a little more?
RAFA: Cover yourself as much as you can!
[Laughs]
DE PAUL: Stop Rafa!...
December, lets see, is summer,
you can be a little risky...
For me you can play a little risky,
for me to say something,
do you remember... Do you remember how he went
with a controversial outfit, to a golden ball gala?
SUAREZ: The embroidery suit?
RAFA: The one with the polka dots?
MESSI: I had several, I had a couple
I had a couple.
DE PAUL: For me something like that, you have to wear something like that.
There was a burgundy suit, one with dots
MESSI: No, that's the black one...
RAFA: The one with the polka dots. The one with the polka dots was tremendous.
He looked like a rug
MESSI: I don't know, I had four years in a row that...
that I wear different ones.
COBRA: For me the one from 2013/2014, that's crazy.
RAFA: Was it a bet that you had lost or something like that?
MESSI: Which one was that? What was the 2014 one ?
COBRA: It was the one that... it was one that you used, Leo.
embroidered, that when you're on the shortlist
with Cristiano and with Robben,
The three of them together, do you remember?
That one was awesome.
MESSI: Good.
COBRA: That one was nice... and I
When I won last year's award,
I wanted to buy one like that, but it didn't fit.
I mean, I looked for one like that, but when I went
to the store it didn't fit. So, well
nothing, i looked for another.
DE PAUL: And for example the first one when he was nominated,
how badly he was dressed,
I think it was 2007.
MESSI: Who?
DE PAUL: You came third, right?
Put that one in, you'll see.
RAFA: Horrible...
COBRA: Nah it was good. Compliant, compliant.
DE PAUL: You were wearing Adidas, idiot.
You were all Adidas, man.
MESSI: No, I was always fine.
The hair style maybe i changed...
but the suit was good...
COBRA: The hair, the beard.
RAFA: No, no. The one from 2007 is a disaster.
And Cobra...if you ...
MESSI: He looked for it, look, this motherfucker looked for it
DE PAUL: Search the photo, search for the photo and show it there!
He is wearing an Adidas outfit !
MESSI: How an Adidas outfit?
DAVO: It's the most normal thing in the world!
It's a jacket with a tie and a shirt.
MESSI: Sure.
RAFA: No, no, no.
There is a previous one is a disaster,
It is unpresentable.
The one with glitter, like Messi's, you have to wear...
COBRA: Don't be bad Rafa.
MESSI: But you have to sunbathe a little for december, dude
to wear something different.
A little bit burned...
DE PAUL: Yes, you are pale, Davo. We are not kidding.
SUAREZ: It reminded me of Rafa number 3...
DE PAUL: Come on, idiot!
RAFA: Well...
DE PAUL: 20 minutes, not even that much!
DAVO: I should, i should, i should
DE PAUL: A little bit of vitamin D.
COBRA: But think that we
We wake up at 4 in the afternoon
Dude, we get up at 4 in the afternoon
and go to sleep at 3 am,
later, 6 in the morning
DAVO: The streamer's life is very difficult
COBRA: It's not easy. It's not easy.
DE PAUL: And what are the schedules like?
You get up at 4pm and then what?
You have lunch?
COBRA: Of course it's lunch time.
DAVO: No, I have dinner after streaming
DAVO: I have dinner around 6 in the morning,
I end stream and i eat.
DE PAUL: Dinner is at 6 am?
DAVO: Kinda, yes.
COBRA: Always healthy.
DE PAUL: Ok, thats ok.
RAFA: For example?
DE PAUL: And lunch is at 5 in the afternoon...
DAVO: Sometimes I skip lunch
to start stream with a light body.
COBRA: I don't skip it. I never skip it.
Because its essential to be nourished.
No, I don't skip it. I don't skip it
Because it couald be bad for me.
It could be bad, just in case.
It's a lot of wear and tear. Streaming is a lot of wear and tear.
You know what i'm saying?
Has it never happened to you in a match?
When you feel like you played badly
Because you were missing something?
That happens to me on the stream. If one day I have a bad stream,
I feel like it's because I lacked a little food
Because I could miss something...
DE PAUL: And on the stream? You always stream
like two or three hours. Always sitting down?....
DAVO: No! I stream like 7 - 8 hours! from 9 at night to 5 am.
DE PAUL: Don't you ever get bored?
DAVO: Y...
DE PAUL: You have to, i think you lose your mind
DAVO: Nah, as long as they pay good, as long as they pay,
no problem.
COBRA: This question is for Leo, Rodri and Luis...
By any chance, if I say "imposter", do you know what that is?
*The IMPOSTOR is a game made popular by La Cobra and Davo*
DE PAUL and SUAREZ: Yeees!
COBRA: Really??
DE PAUL: And how can we not know?
COBRA: Ah! very good, very good.
SUAREZ. Ah, the kids, the kids...
DE PAUL: Look, you don't know...
MESSI: Yes, stupid if I play with my kids.
SUAREZ: Of course, the kids play with him. They got it from you...
COBRA: Seriously!?
DAVO: Stop, stop, are you playing impostor with your children?
MESSI: Yes, dude.
DE PAUL: You know which one we play
when we are bored with the dwarf (Messi)?
DAVO: Which one?
DE PAUL: " I can tell you? Three players..."
DAVO: Oh, "liar, liar"!
COBRA: Yes...
DE PAUL: "that played..." That one
MESSI: This guy sucks at it
COBRA: With Davo we have literally 20 uploaded
videos to YouTube of it, because we have no more ideas.
"I can tell you seven players from Zambia"
because we no longer have
any more ideas. We have been
stealing for two years with that...
DAVO: Match is over. 6 - 0 Deportivo LSM.
We won!
SUAREZ: Close Rafa...
RAFA: Lets go!
Lets go
DE PAUL: 6-0 dude.
COBRA: All ours right Davo? Aura of streamers.
DE PAUL: But 6-0 away...
Did the players from Montevideo went partying with you
yesterday after the awards?
[Laughs]
DE PAUL: Away team scores six goals?
either the team is very good or Deportivo is...
eh?
DAVO: Its because we are here!
COBRA: But Davo, Boca lost the match
Aren't you going to say anything? You have to defend us.
DAVO: No, but it is Montevideo Boca Juniors. Stop stupid...
COBRA: Ah, ah...
SUAREZ: Listen... Well,
I wanted to thank you
to both of you and Rafa.
COBRA: No, please, my pleasure, thank you very much guys.
SUAREZ: Thank you very much for the good vibes.
Thanks to Rodri who just woke up too
and Leo and thats it I think
I think we had a good time and... nothing more
I don't know what to do now. I don't know, Rafa,
you are used to this,
what needs to be done now? We end it thats it?
RAFA: Yes, now we close the transmission,
thank you basically
to the stars of this transmission
Davo and Cobra, who are awesome
...who made a very big effort.
SUAREZ: "nine" and "the leek"
MESSI: Are you going to sleep now or are you staying...?
RAFA: ...the Nine and the leek
DAVO: Naaa, I'm leaving now...
DAVO: Now I watch the first half of Manchester game and I'm going to sleep
RAFA: He's sleeping until 7 pm, Leo
He will sleep until 7 pm.
DAVO: No, tomorrow I have to go out .
Tomorrow I have to go out again.
I have to be fine for the night today.
RAFA: Wow it's incredible
COBRA: Now I'm going to work ...
Now I'm going to work to the construction site
and this continues. This goes on long.
SUAREZ: What work? What work?
COBRA: I'm doing some things at home and I'm working.
SUAREZ: Look... on a Saturday
RAFA: No, he doesn't even get up from the chair.
He doesn't even get up from the chair. He doesn't even get up to pee
COBRA: Oh, shut up Rafa, you just asked...
you were lost...
No, really guys, thanks.
DE PAUL: Root for us tonight, boys.
RAFA: To Luis, Leo and "Diosito"
that joined the stream too
a big hug
that we always watched him
in the Marginal and the truth...
It was very good.
DAVO: Well, the one that scored against us the other day,
Barracas' goal looks like you, don't you think?
DAVO: Insúa
COBRA: Insúa
DE PAUL: The one with the braids...
So, are you watching the Inter Miami game tonight?
or are you streaming? ...
RAFA: Cerro is playing tonight, Rodri, if not ... In a good way...
COBRA: Inter Miami - Nashville
DAVO: We will watch it
SUAREZ: Stop, explain what Cerro is
because Rodri doesn't know what Cerro is, idiot
RAFA: But if you don't know, you have no idea about football.
Cerro is the biggest team in Uruguay.
They just beatted Peñarol, today they are going to beat Nacional
SUAREZ: It's like Chacarita from Argentina.
DAVO: No! Weaker than Chacarita...
RAFA: The greatest...
The biggest club, like Central... (Newell's rival team, Messi's former club)
It's seriously big, like Central.
Look how he raised his head.
SUAREZ: Well, people...
COBRA: Thank you.
SUAREZ: Thank you. I send you a big hug
COBRA: Take care, see you later
DE PAUL: Bye band!
RAFA: Close there.
COBRA: Bye bye!