But sometimes you can go, “Oh my god, I need to save.
If I save, the other fans”. All of that, and it goes through your mind.
That’s my question, how do you deal with these thoughts?
The moment of the strike is when I say, okay, this is my moment.
I need to focus only on myself.
Brilliant!
Oh, chilly mate. Really, really cold.
Been 12 years in this country and still freezing for me.
I got a little break between games, so I'm going to work a little bit
on penalties and on the mental side.
It's good to always, you know, when you're successful,
winning tournaments, big tournaments,
it's so good to keep trying and improve yourself.
It's a big moment for me. I always feel like
it's an opportunity to shine and to show how good I am,
how strong I am in penalties.
I never think I'm going to be the hero.
It's just about enjoying the moment.
Since a very young age,
since I remember probably seven, eight,
I’ve always been lucky in penalty shootouts you know.
I win more than lose.
When you're young, you just play for joy.
When you're older, you play for a team, you play for a club,
so you need to perform in a different way.
It's hard to go to every goalie's mind,
but sometimes goalies, when you go to a penalty shootout,
they can have a little bit of pressure on themselves thinking,
oh, if you haven’t saved one, then everyone will look on me
and they would think I had a bad game or I'm not good enough.
How you doing? You good?
Yeah. Good. You?
Emi or Dibu?
Emi is fine.
Yeah, in Europe I'm Emi.
If you come over here, let me explain it to you real quick.
This is your brain activity right here.
And then we see the different brain states and what we are trying
to help you with is to better get into the zone.
So when you’re in that optimal brain state,
then the sound will play on the speaker, this one right here
and this will indicate how well you’re managing pressure
and how well focussed you are right now.
So Emi can you go through your routine
and just explain a little bit what you do in a game please?
I move side to side. It’s just for me to get that fire up.
Sometimes move quicker, sometimes move slower,
depends how I feel during the day.
And then when it's about to strike is when you think, okay,
I don't want to go early 'cause they wait for you.
They're still looking at you. They're very clever nowadays.
So it's about moving a little bit
to not show them any sign of which way I'm going
and then fire at the last minute.
Because if I'm going there, by the moment he's about to strike,
he sees me, so they would put it that way.
Make sure I don’t open my legs too wide to be ready to push.
First we're going to do penalties towards this side.
Five to this.
Then we’ll do five either direction, you don't know which side.
And then we do five random.
Remember the sound.
Yeah.
So it's this moment. When I say focus, that's when you focus and get clear.
You know what I mean?
So we start with the first five.
Focus!
Okay, good. Nice.
Nice. Good.
Alright, three more.
Focus.
Nice. Great.
When you have this fluid motion that you had,
for example at the World Cup.
It was really fluid, the timing was perfect,
when it touched his foot.
That's when you make a save, timing.
Timing.
You have the pressure of getting there, right?
Because if you are basically here with the hand,
it's a higher chance of you saving it, right?
So that's why you really extend.
Negative pressure is something that can limit you to perform at your best.
So it can also limit you from jumping as far, if your movement is not fluid.
So that's why you want to really be optimally focused
to get to the furthest distance
and have the highest percentage of saving a penalty.
And it's that confidence that makes you deal with that pressure, right?
If you're not sure where's it's going to go
and you change your mind during the run,
that's it. You don't save it.
Some of the goalies when he's running, they keep changing
where he's going low, high, mid.
I'm choosing one side.
I'm not thinking he's going mid, low, high.
I'm just thinking it's going right.
And that's part of dealing with the pressure is the preparation, right?
Yeah but the preparation in the World Cup, in the final,
Messi told me that he was going, he likes high
So I prepared myself the body shape, yeah, he's going there.
But then I dive right, high, but the ball went low,
so my preparation
was to go high, then in the moment went low.
So I'm more about my intuition as well.
Not just about the stats.
Just read what's in front of you in the moment.
Nice.
Ok.
Good strikes though.
When, for example, you go in a shootout,
let's say the first four score and the pressure comes for the fifth,
how do you deal with that situation?
The first thing you need to believe in yourself.
None of this distracting them or try to go into their head.
I think more about my timing. My footwork.
Let's say if you guess the side,
then you don't save it, then it’s ah
you get upset but you're doing something good,
which is guessing the side.
Then the problem is when it's a penalty shootout
and you go nowhere near,
I think oof, “it's not my day.”
But I always think, I always save one.
I could have saved two easily.
In five, you save two, you win.
I’ve got less chances. I'm always against the odds here.
Your body shape says you’re going there, 100%. Yeah!
Can you specify that a little bit?
His body shape, his hand is stuck to his body.
When he's going across, he leaves his arm a little bit more.
But this one, he kept the hands close to him
so I knew he was going that way.
Brilliant!
Your focus was very very clear.
And that's where I even noticed it in your eyes.
In your eyes now you're excited. Now it's the part that you love.
Alright, last one, last one. Let's go. Focus!
He's done something different now.
because he doesn't want to show me the body shape, you see, no?
He’s getting to you. Huh? You do your thing.
He’s going hard.
Ohhh!
You see, nearly missed!
Good job.
Okay, we're going to look into the data now.
First of all, you need a proper challenge.
Yeah.
For you, it's like if you're underactivated...
There's no point to do it. Yeah, it's normal.
Was that always like that? That's my question to you.
Were you like because it's a character thing,
it’s your personality also, right?
No, I need a challenge. Yeah.
I need someone to wind you up and to fire you up.
To give you fuel.
Because the one thing that I found was really interesting,
you're 85% more in the zone when it goes anywhere
compared to left or right.
When the challenge is really high, you're actually more in the zone.
And I find that actually quite fascinating because it really represents
your personality and the way you act and this kind of stuff.
That’s interesting, right?
Yeah. It makes you more comfortable.
It makes you more comfortable.
It does yeah.
I play to be fired up and to lose all my nerves.
But sometimes you can go, “Oh my god, I need to save.
If I save, the other fans”. all of that, and it goes through your mind.
That’s my question, how do you deal with these thoughts?
The moment of the strike is when I say
okay, this is my moment.
I need to focus only on myself.
Ok so in that moment it's like switch off?
Switch off and it's me against the ball against him.
Not against three billion people watching on the TV in a World Cup final.
As simple as that.
You know I used to say to Messi to shoot
penalty to you to get that confidence
and I can't save anything, so it doesn't help.
It doesn't help.
It’s actually bad for your confidence!
It’s actually bad for me, so I'm not practicing too much.
Thank you so much. Appreciate it.
Thank you, brothers. It was a pleasure.
Well, one thing we found was that he really needs the challenge.
So with that, he increases actually with the focus. It's quite fascinating.
I got 85% I think when I'm more in the zone
and the pressure is there
and I focus more when the pressure's on, which is interesting.
And that's something that I do.
When the pressure is on, is when I play the best. So it's good.
You know when you're a young goalkeeper, you listen to what the club says
and you try to do everything for the club,
but sometimes you need to listen to yourself
and just follow your gut and take risks.
If you don't take the risk, you won't have big rewards.
You have to put in your hard work,
your technique, your mental preparation, all these kinds of things,
and then you just give it your best shot.
And if all those things come together, it's like a puzzle.
Focus!
When it’s that amount of pressure, I really enjoy it
because I always think it's a game.
At the end of the day, it’s just football, so you can win or lose.
But it’s always good to have fun.