Like how he walks, how he holds himself, how he speaks.
Like the very best.
I'm the very, very best.
Like, even if he doesn't feel it, he shows it.
Yeah, he was making me believe that I was the best in the league.
Even though I never think that, I never think I'm the best, I'm doing the best season.
But he was making me think, you are the best in the league.
Well, how does he do that just constantly telling you constantly?
Just remember confidence to the point of arrogance.
So I used to think that.
You're right, I can be arrogant in the way I play, but she's that...
to give me confidence, nothing else.
Not to show everyone, oh, he's arrogant.
It's just to believe yourself that you are the best in the league.
And I think if you've catered for most things in training, like match specific, we've covered it all, mate.
You're ready.
Like, nothing can stop you now.
Like, it's the shoulders back.
And it's that, like, training his brain to believe it.
Like, before, when he first came in, it would be more of a...
it'd be more of a, like, Arsenal-Villa at the time or like that.
So he's coming to a team that were completely different for him.
go away with Argentina sometimes and come back and go frustrated.
It's not the level.
And he wouldn't put his shoulders back and go like,
I'm too good for this, he'd go, that's frustrating me and this is frustrating me.
I need to get to this.
I need the players to get to that.
I need, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
That's not, that's not your job.
You ain't got to worry about that.
You just be the best.
Like you just do what you do day in, day out gaming.
game out, the rest will speak for itself.
Did that help you at first when you signed for Villa where
You knew you were going to be busy and you were busy, wasn't you?
You're making saves.
You're having to be called on.
in every single game to save Aston Villa, basically.
Did that help sort of raise that confidence as well?
Yeah, it was huge.
It was huge.
Normally, Arsenal and a big club, a national team,
you get two shots, but two good ones, 1v1 or a clear shot.
and Avila was just deflection after deflection, crosses, but I thought it was good, I'm reactive.
I'm really good in the air, kicking a lot of balls.
I wasn't used to kick so many balls.
I'm really good kicker of the ball.
So I feel like, oh, if I get all these things right,
I can really help the team.
But then I was going with the national team.
When I was playing for Argentina, I was like,
Made that's so easy.
You know, it was so easy.
Why why is it so much easier?
Why?
Because I was doing so much for the villa.
So much.
Involved in everything.
I made 160 saves I think in the first season.
So when I was going with the national team, making one or two saves, clean sheet, clean sheet, clean sheet.
I think I got like 30 clean sheets in 37 games for my country.
So it was so easy.
do you notice the opposition?
So when you go away with Argentina, they won't press you so much because they know they're happy to let you have the ball, basically.
Again, that...
Kind of takes the stress off a bit, doesn't it?
The first few games with the national team, the manager did not want me to play from the back.
No, he hated it.
Now in the national team, we play a lot with the back because they also in my team, they watch you every game.
for Aston Villa, so they trust you more.
And in Manchester, it's like,
He went at half-time.
We played Uruguay at home.
He hates playing from the back.
He's that old school manager.
It was me, McAllister, Enzo Fernandez, De Paul playing with Romero.
They're all good footballers.
Yeah, ballers.
So we were doing the 1-2, 1-2 from the back.
If you guys want to play...
You do it.
But I don't like it.
It was a halftime.
And we went, we're going to keep doing it.
So that's a national team.
The level of me is just incredible.
I can imagine.
Let's sort of fast forward with Villa a little bit then.
I think the progression of Villa over the last couple of years in particular has been incredible.
It was probably the catalyst was when Unai Emery came into Aston Villa, took over from Steven Gerrard.
I'm on the sack.
Pardon, sorry?
And I got the sack.
And then you got the sack, unfortunately.
um actually that might be an interesting thing to talk about actually is
is how that dynamic works then is because a new manager comes in, he brings his own staff in, cuts, unfortunately gets sacked.
How does that work from a goalie's perspective then when you are expected to just start up with another goalie coach?
I think having the same spot director and the same CEO, I thought he was fine.
I said, no, I can't.
Stay here, we're all for you.
You brought me here.
I'm Argentinian number one.
I put my name...
higher obviously in the ranks and I said you'll be fine and then I remember saying like look
I'm getting sacked and it was a big shock for me.
You know what I'm saying?
We knew the relationship we had.
how comfortable I was with him on and off the pitch.
that I went to the club, to the CEO, to the director, and said, there's nothing we can do.
as a manager decision that's a new staff decision and
I knew Javi, so I knew Javi wouldn't do that.
probably meet him, talk to him and then work alongside him because that's how I know Javi.
So it was quite difficult knowing he doesn't have a club.
Obviously, I didn't have that relationship day in, day out.
So it was a difficult period for me last year.
because I was going to a World Cup as well, so I couldn't really
a lot of changes a lot of changes so it was hard that season was hard for me
And what's that like from your point of view then because I'm guessing that that's probably
one of the biggest sort of worries and scares of being a football coach or a goalie coach, assistant manager, anything like that,
If that manager gets sacked, then you're kind of fearing for your job as well.
Because it's without...
It's not within your control.
How do you not take that personally?
I think you have to when you take the job you feel like it's part and parcel a little bit so when you take the job you know there's a chance of it happening so you have to
put that to the back of your mind and go right okay if it happens it happens
And I'm all about the development of the goalies, right?
I'm all about...
leaving the place better than when I found it.
I'm all about every day, if I get the sack, I get the sack, but I've left it better.
Miles better.
That goalie unit, the whole goalie unit.
That unit is, that department.
is so much better than when I found it and when I took control of it.
And I can, like...
I don't know, like when you get the sack and you don't know why you've got the sack, you can't learn, can you?
So it's like somebody who doesn't sat me down and gone, I've sat you because of these reasons.
And you go, right, that's fair enough.
I'll learn from that.
That was the thing for me.
I wanted somebody to sit me down and go, right, you've not done this and you've not done that, and that was poor.
And then you can go away and go, right, that's how it is.
to improve.
But is it not just circumstantial?
You know that deep down you go...
it's because they're bringing in their own literally collateral damage isn't it they're bringing in their own stuff so in the end you just go right okay I've just been sacked and that's it but
to get sacked and then see someone that you've worked with
like so closely win the World Cup was just like,
was everything for me.
It was massive.
All my family, we went on holiday.
We're like, we all watched it together.
He said, I promise you, if you win the World Cup, you give me a FaceTime after the game.
That's what I was going to ask you.
How quickly after you won the World Cup did you... In the changing room.
In the changing room.
Yeah, yeah.
But to be fair, the club was good, I promise you.
we gave him a year of his salary, you know, we're going to look after
A couple million quid, I think, wasn't it?
Yeah, three or five.
Lira.
No, the club kept their promise, so that's what it's about.
They're quite good.
And it is, it's one of them, isn't it?
I kind of, when I got, I've never been out football since I was 16, ever.
And I got the sack and I just went, oh, God.
I got a family again, eh?
yeah like you just need that breather it's not until you stop you go oh my god like
I needed that.
I needed the break.
I needed like four or five months of just like calm.
So interesting you say that because Rob Paul Robinson said this exact same thing, didn't they?
He said, from 16 to 38.
That's all you need.
Like the pressures of football, you don't realise, like...
while you're in it you can't see the woods for the trees like you don't realize the pressure and
and the time it's taken daily like getting in at half seven
You're not leaving until half six, seven o'clock at night.
You're going home.
Repeat.
Pressure of winning games.
How did you say when you kind of took you you kind of took that breath what I
What was your mentality like?
Were you, I want to get back in, or let's just take a minute?
Let's just take a minute.
needed it.
I really needed it.
And I had a couple of offers that I thought, I can't, and decent ones.
And I thought, I'm not ready.
Like, I can't do it.
I needed the break.
I felt kind of burnt out.
I felt like
And it wasn't until I stopped.
If I'd have kept going, I'd have been fine.
But I stopped and gone, Jesus, like, I need it.
Did you start to appreciate the things that you missed out?
Because I know when you retired from Watford, Ben, you...
you found pleasure in the small things in life, like having a weekend, going to the Friday night.
Friday night's incredible.
Do you know this?
They...
You can go to the pub and stuff.
You can have a beer and that.
chill you ain't gonna worry about getting up in the morning because the most you see yourself though footballers they kind of get a lot more insular towards the end of the week and
because that stress starts to come on, doesn't it?
And it's like, the game's here tomorrow,
You haven't got any of that.
It's incredible, let me be honest.
It's incredible.
I don't want to feel it here.
Give me a few more years.
I go all in, so they mean everything to me, like everything.
I do whatever it takes to make them better.
all day, every day, constantly in my mind, like, how do I do this?
Where am I going to do this?
How am I going to make him better?
What am I going to do in training?
How are we going to be at the game?
Is what we need to do to implement the game, the following game?
What do we put rightly into the next game?
And it's just like, boom, boom, boom, boom, boom.
And you just need to go.
I've got to say, I...
I've worked with some really good goalie coaches in my time.
I have never seen anybody
take on this goalie department unit and make it their baby like I have seen Neil Cutler do.
It genuinely is.
It's like your baby, isn't it?
It's like the whole thing.
And you're talking goalie coaches underneath of you,
You're talking like academy goalies, young goalies under 12, 34, all the way through.
You're talking a lot of people, aren't you?
And you came in, I remember at West Brom and it was like, yeah, this is all of mine and I will take charge of it.
It was good to see, to be fair.
I feel like I've improved as I got older and more knowledgeable.
And since being with them and since...
Obviously me going on to what he did even more confidence to take that on and
like even more confidence to implement my ideas and my philosophy and what I think
to other coaches because you do you gain that bit more every step you go a bit more confident a bit more knowledgeable a bit more experienced and then
you feel like you can implement it with more, I don't know, a bit more aggressively.
Authority.
A bit more authority.
It's proven.
It works.
Yeah, it's proven.
I mean, like you were saying, with every loan that you get, I know that loan at Katafe that didn't quite work out.
getting sacked, it all just makes, rightly or wrongly, it makes you better, doesn't it?
And Xavi's a really good coach, by the way.
he's come on and you've just kept doing that and that's massively important to me like it's not somebody come in and
ripped apart what we've done over those years Javi's come in and gone no we just keep building we just keep getting better and it's just that's massively important
Emi, can we ask and pick your brain?
Because I wasn't aware of this rule.
Kurtz, were you?
Incredible.
It's like they just make up rules when they want to, basically.
I want to talk about the Conference League quarterfinal, the penalty shootout.
So you've already got a yellow card in the game.
And then you get another yellow card in the penalty shootout.
Were you aware that that meant you were going to miss the first leg of the semi-final?
Mate, I was like...
You know, it was the game started.
So the fan was having a go at me because I was in France.
Obviously they remember the World Cup final.
So the fans were straight up muted since the start of the game.
And the Reds, the first goal kick, he went, I'm going to book you.
I said, mate, I'm just getting the ball.
I was asking the ball for the ball boy.
And because they probably were French, they would not give me the ball.
I had to go and get it.
And he was like, stop wasting time.
I'm going to book you.
First goal kick.
So...
I got booked after 25 minutes, never seen before.
Losing 1-0, got booked.
Don't ask me why.
The game was on and the penalty shootout.
So the Red was like straight up going at me because he knew me, probably watched videos about me.
So he knew how I behaved in the penalty shootout.
uh so save the first plane obviously i shoot the crowd because they were having a stick at me at the
Whole games, insulting me, throwing me coins, lighters, the whole game.
But then I see the first band and their players must go into the crowd.
So there was no ball on the pitch.
So then I turned and I was asking the ball to the ball boy.
I didn't want my teammate to wait to take the pen because I know the pressure.
are you aware of that now are you fully aware of that now please can you give me the ball and the ref went and she's with the yellow so I'm off
I got a yellow I'm off I said ref I'm asking for the ball and then he was just walking off
I thought, am I off or did he gave me the yellow?
Are you thinking, don't say anything?
Get back in goal.
And you see all the players from Lille, he's got yellow, he's got yellow.
I said, no, no, no, it's not off.
I know he's got yellow.
He was a ref.
And Douglas was, Dougie, just tell him.
because I was going to be the captain, but I said, Doggy, you just keep the armband.
I don't want it.
for the shooter.
I just want to concentrate on penalties, you know.
And then they told me after the game that I missed the semi-final because I got two yellows
in one game, and they say that
When you play in a semi-final, quarter-finals, then you get two yellows.
It doesn't count in shootout.
Shootout is like a different game.
I said, how can I be suspended for the first leg in the semi-final?
If the shootout is not part of the leg.
So it worked the same as if you got a yellow card in the first leg and a yellow card in the second leg, you would miss the first leg of the semifinal then?
That's how it worked.
No, I had a yellow at Villa Park for time-wasting.
You've got three yellow cards and two... And then I've got a yellow card in the corner.
in the second leg but I asked the club he said if I get a yellow card
In France, will I miss the semi-final?
I said, no, with two yellows, you won't miss the semi-final.
So I said, okay, so that was, you know, for if we winning,
Late in the game, I would just calm myself down.
Even if I get a yellow, I don't mean the semi-final.
It was checked.
It was all good.
And then when it's three yellows, the UEFA said, what are we doing now?
So they decided at that time, they made the app that couldn't play the semifinals.
Like they punished me.
Have for having three yellows there that I think they might have all sort of looked at you haven't gone There's no way on this earth anybody
can be that much of a shit house, right?
To get three yellow cards in two games, it's impossible, right?
I put all my money that no one knew in football that...
If you get two yellows in one game, you will not get a red card.
No one knew in football.
I would just like to say, are you aware now though, you know, that when, if you're playing in a game,
and it goes to a penalty shootout, are you aware that everybody knows exactly how that penalty shootout is going to end?
Yes.
Do you know that?
Even their players.
I remember against Lille, the ball was in between
me and the little player, I can't remember his name.
So I ran into the ball, he was sprinting.
Because he knew me.
And then I got the ball and I left it on the floor like that.
pulled him off already so then when he missed a pen he smashed the ball into the crowd like
really upset for my god I went into his head already
It's so easy now.
It's easy.
Mate, and I thought, it's a young lad, Gomez, from Lille.
And I promise you, for my kid, when he was putting the ball on the floor, he was shaking.
Wow.
That's when my mum's life, it was actually shaking so far.
But I already had a yellow, so I thought if you eat a reference,
booked me in the shootout, how can I be off?
So I couldn't do anything.
stupid or what I wanted to do because I already had a yellow in the game.
Incredible.
World class.
Weird.
I'm thinking everything.
Incredible.
Shall we do some World Cup chat?
Oh, we've got to do World War II.
Right, this is the bit earlier, right?
When I was prepping for this Emi, I was giggling to myself.
I was like...
Honestly, I was so excited about this.
Giddy.
Giddy is what I was, right?
We've got to start with... So forget the rest of the game, right?
The rest of the game was incredible.
It was fantastic.
It was...
about as good a, not even World Cup fight, as good a game as football as you could wish to watch, wasn't it?
a guarantee playing as well.
It's like it was written by a Hollywood producer or something.
It was phenomenal, right?
I'm going to transport you though to the 122nd minute and 40 seconds, 42 seconds actually.
And Kolo Mwani just gets put through and...
And I want to know now from a goalkeeper's perspective, everything.
Absolutely everything.
Everything that's going through your mind, cuts I want to know you, technical details,
Everything that's gone on, break it down for me, Emi.
The first thing I always say, I didn't think it was that good, the save.
Wow.
I made better saves than that, but...
I expect Otamendi to miss the ball.
You'd already read that.
Look Ben, I was having a comfortable game
you know really comfortable really good with the ball of my feet 75 minutes then i can see two goals or three goals in
Two minutes.
Out of nothing with two penalties and one goal we impacted and maybe I should have a strong hand on it.
And then I was so comfortable,
calm in that situation for, oh no, Otis is going to miss it, Otis is going to miss it, Otis is going to miss it.
And then he does it.
So then I'm,
I'm calm because I'm already expecting him to miss it.
If I'm not expecting Otamendi to miss a ball, I don't think I'm going to save that ball.
And I'm, you know, I remember the Maria school.
against Brazil in the Maracanã when Edison came out and Di Maria just looped over him.
So if you're running, he's going to loop it.
So Edison was running out towards him.
It was Di Maria and we won the Copa America because Di Maria looped him.
1-1-0.
So I thought, that came into my head, even though it was so close, I said, I'm staying.
And then how the ball was travelling, then I was adjusting to the ball.
Because if I was staying too deep, he had a pass.
He could square the pass into, I think it was in pass.
So I thought, okay, I close the goal, I close the goal, I close the goal.
And then because, you know, Ben, you've been a goalkeeper.
So if you run to him, they're still looking at you.
Yeah.
Even though his head's down.
Even though they're down, they can look at you.
So then, you know, any striker, top class, whoosh,
That's it, you lose the World Cup.
So I keep my cool, I go into the angle, and then when he's about to shoot, I fall.
I work with German goalkeepers, with English goalkeepers and South American goalkeepers.
normally the German they stay up with the hands high and they choose robotic
The English light, they spread.
In South America, they guess.
That's the style.
So if I guess and then I guess wrong, then
Game over.
So if I stay like German...
maybe, you know, you can't really go sideways.
So if I spread,
Maybe I don't cover how much I want to cover.
Okay, this is all going through your head, yeah?
This is in these split seconds.
By the time he's going to shoot, he'll say, what am I doing?
You need to make a decision.
Or you go, you stay, or you jump, or you go low.
So I thought, look, the way I was cutting the angle diagonally, I thought,
if he goes across, he can miss on the bullet.
If he goes across,
The ball is going away from the goal and I'm going diagonally that way
to the towards the left so for that left side is quite open
because I'm going forwards.
I know where the goal is.
I know exactly where the goal is because I can see the penalty spot there.
So I thought, he's going to go there.
This is the thing we work a lot.
body shape regarding to the ball.
The ball is bouncing.
So I don't keep my hands low.
Normally it's a 1v1 low.
You keep your hands quite low.
The ball is bouncing, so if I keep my hands low, I leave all this open.
So I thought, I'm guessing...
without actually diving, that's going to go left.
So my left leg and my left hand is really strong.
you know you put rock solid in your hands.
So I thought, please hit me, my face straight to the ball.
And then I'm praying that the ball is going to go left.
Then you can save it or not.
But then I did not move, you know, keep myself square.
It's just brain that's going to go to that side, you know.
and this one and you just leave it just in case you know strong as well
And it was so quick that we nearly won it.
And then obviously after the game, the save was huge.
At the time, it was just so quick.
Massive like.
Everything you just said there is hours and hours and hours of work that he's done over the years.
holding his shape for long periods of time and having the balls to go, nah,
I'm not triggering, I'm not falling back.
My hand position in relation to ball distance and body position in relation to ball distance is spot on.
And you ain't beating me.
Like you can see, it's just like, I'm not conceding.
Like if you stay up and hold, don't trigger, don't fall back.
So biomechanically,
Perfect.
His shoulders haven't rotated.
His hands haven't triggered.
The body weight's not falling back.
Face.
Can you explain what triggering is for the viewers, please?
So a lot of goalies, well, goalies can trick.
So as soon as the ball's hit, what does your body want to do?
Naturally, your body will want to go, woof, it's coming quick now.
So a lot of goalies will trigger the hands backwards to come forward.
But as soon as your hands go backwards, how does that affect your body weight?
What's your body weight going to want to do?
It's going to want to send you backwards, which means then you can't get onto your leading leg.
You end up sweeping.
Like things will go through you if you stay forwards and you keep your hands in good positions and you keep your chin forward and shoulders forward and
you can react to the ball in split seconds like you can and you will naturally because your hands will always move quicker than the ball
So your hands will move quicker than the ball ever does.
So if you start to trigger,
then your hands can't get to the ball because they're smoothing your body weight.
So then you can't get, as soon as you come into neutral or negative,
then you can't get onto your leading leg you can't literally cannot transfer
So that's hours and hours of work, like hold, hold.
And like the stuff we did with the rebound net,
has helped him with that.
It's like, I'm going to have to hold, I'm going to have to hold, I'm going to have to hold.
And some of the saves that he makes
holding his shakes for a long period of time, and how quickly he can get onto his leading legs through
Holding shape, transfer, push.
Not triggering.
it doesn't matter how fast that ball's coming or how hard it's hit or how close it is
you don't if your body weight remains forward and you're not triggering from the pace of the ball
you're going to transfer.
A simple way of saying it is flinching, basically.
Yeah, but in a big way.
If you watch that set back,
Back in the World Cup, no flinching, just like holding, holding, holding.
To keep your face forward, right?
When somebody is about to kick a ball from five yards away.
Natural human reaction is to try and close your eyes and you move your head to the side.
Watch it.
It is face forward.
And it is, if this comes right in my face, I'm going to watch it.
So I'm like, you know.
We used to work a lot on, we've got no, I can't beat you.
I've got nowhere to go.
If you hold and you don't trigger, I cannot score.
You're the best in the world and I can't beat you.
I cannot beat you, I cannot beat you.
I used to say it all the time.
Even now that I'm working with deflection nets, there's a new way that I've found.
You know the medicine balls?
In the gym.
I put, you know those poles, when you put poles to run?
Yeah.
I put three poles and the medicine bowl on the top in between.
So it's kind of like when you're standing, you can't see the ball.
So you need to go down.
Yeah.
and look it, or you go high and you, mate, try it, it's perfect.
Go in goal, Ben, put three poles, you know, the running poles, the one you've got zigzag.
and put the medicine ball in the middle and go in goal.
Put two or three.
Just to try and see the ball.
He's great.
And you know who helped me, John, the physio.
I remember I had a hamstring injury, so I trained a few days with him, I thought,
man, this is great for goalkeeping.
So I put in the...
But sometimes I put it 10 yards and then I start, you know, I like to catch balls every time.
Catch, catch, catch, catch up.
So I was catching balls.
I said, no, no, bring it six meters now.
And then I'm pushing it.
Now four meters.
Goals, goals, goals.
And I'm working on four meters because I'm catching on eight.
I'm pushing away in six, four goals.
by two weeks, I'm saving the one for me.
You're unlocking the next.
level then you go to three and then two it's like video games exactly I use it that way so I find a new way now it's like a new toy for me oh shit
if anybody had any doubts whether goalkeepers are a different breed honestly this is this is it in a nutshell isn't it this is
I honestly think that if outfielders had the same kind of interest in their craft
the same dedication to the craft of stopping the ball going in the back of the net, you'd have 11 Lionel Messi's on the pitch every night.
every Saturday afternoon, wouldn't you?
It's as simple as that.
That's important.
I think you spoke about John Whitney, who's a sports scientist, strength and conditioning coach.
mainly outfield, but with such an in-depth knowledge of the biomechanics or biomechanical movement
That he can help you a lot couldn't he probably helped you a lot with India within your physio and your rehab like and
If you've got that in-depth knowledge of biomechanics and how goalkeepers move, huge.
Right then, mate.
So you've made the save.
Full-time whistle's gone.
Penalty shootout, okay?
This is... We were watching it, wasn't we?
And we knew what was gonna happen.
It was inevitable.
and this is no slight on Hugo Lloris, but
when you put Hugo Lloris in goal and then you put you in goal, the size difference is just phenomenal.
so sort of daunting and you just failed the goal.
I don't think it's size though, is it?
What do you think it is?
I think it's personality.
Aura.
I think it's, again, it's,
It boils down to confidence to the point of arrogance.
You see the look on the face and the way you hold yourself.
Small goalies can strip well, yeah?
Like you've got some small goalies that you think are big on the pitch when they're quite small.
And some goalies that are big and look small.
The big ones that look small in the goal and come off the pitch and go, yeah, actually quite big.
Yeah, it's true, yeah.
And it's like, it's what you bring in terms of your personality.
Yeah.
it's like the um we went to man united away and the ronaldo thing remember it yeah yeah
And who was it who missed the penalty?
Bruno.
And we spoke about it before, didn't we?
What, what, what?
What little details can you bring into your game that's going to make you this person?
And it has to be that.
personality.
You've got to bring an aura, a personality, a real like.
I'm not going to get beat.
Whereas it's not down to size.
It's your presence.
We said that when we were watching the game.
We actually said that
And he's making the goal look small.
Yeah.
And like you were saying earlier on, cuts about...
how you conduct yourself, you know, shoulders back.
It's that aura, isn't it?
Making yourself big.
Bigger.
You know, he'd look in his eyes and go, he's saving it.
Yeah.
It's not because he's big.
It's just like...
Yeah.
Even I suppose it's a lanky after getting to you.
Why do you put it so high?
I've never seen you put in that high.
So may
i don't know where to go you you made it i have to go really yeah
I actually asked Solanki, I said, it's a great pen, but why do you go so high?
We watch penalties, so you never go that high.
I said, mate, I have to change something.
I have to go there.
Because he knows you'll save it otherwise.
Yeah, that's fascinating.
You know, you can get there to the side.
I know you can get to the side, so I have to put a right in the corner.
This is what this, that, that I will only back myself up a little bit and say, when I say about size, right?
Some of the penalties,
you are nearly touching the post.
By the time you finish a sable, when you get your hand on the ball,
you're nearly on the post.
That's not size, is it?
It's got to be size.
No.
What is it?
It's...
speed power push and power you don't have to yeah i think i believe that is power and timing yeah
Timing.
I'm all over this.
I'm not saying, I always say if you get the timing right,
I'll reach a post just the timing if you're going to save a penalty you don't
go to the ball, dear.
To be fair, anyone can save a penalty.
Go through the ball, go past the ball, his speed and his power, how quick he can go from here to there.
Right?
And it has to be like, boom.
So it's timing and speed and power.
Speed equals distance divided by... How quickly you can transfer your body weight, isn't it?
how quickly you can get onto your leading leg.
I've got to ask you, Emi,
Some of the viewers might think this is a strange question, but we've had professor Steve Peters on psychologists on
And they talk about the gold medal syndrome.
Now, World Cup's the biggest prize you can win.
Did you have a moment where you had that...
gold medal syndrome where you almost had a low after or not.
No.
Not just high.
Always high, yeah.
But...
After the shoot, after the World Cup, when I was home, I said,
i reached my dream i can't go any higher because the feeling i had after that work up is like
Even if I win the next one, I already know what I felt.
So now what's next?
When you win the Golden Glove in the Copa America,
You win the Super Cup, you win the Golden Glove and the World Cup.
It's like, what else can I win?
Like, if you win the best on Yashin, which I won, it's just individual, you know.
I wanted the World Cup since I was five years old.
My boy is obsessed with the World Cup.
That's why I wanted to win.
But now that's when the psychology comes.
What's next?
How can I be motivated when I already reached my dreams?
It kind of answers my question.
Like I said, maybe I positioned it incorrectly and low, but...
I always find a way.
I want to get Aston Villa in the Champions League.
I was upset with it.
I was like, I need to get this club because he...
I won the World Cup after 38 years in Argentina, won the Copa America after 30 years,
We never beat Brazil in the Maracanã.
The first game that they lost in qualifiers in history was against us.
in December, so I always find leader target like
huge target because let's say you play for Man United you qualify you make top four it's
You know, it's a big season.
Even if he's starting on with Chelsea, it's more or less anyone can do it or, you know, it's a big club.
Aston Villa 42 years I said what if
I can do it.
What if we're done?
It's something like...
it's hard to do special it's it's that's me it's challenging myself
That's the equivalent of Man City winning the league, isn't it?
Really, let's be honest.
Villa getting in the Champions League is...
It's huge.
It's absolutely monumental.
And for me, and I say that to my mum, I say that to my agents,
It means more staying in a club like Villa
and deliver what I was dreaming.
It's like winning a title with Argentina.
So what next?
You've got to win the Champions League then because you've ticked everything else off, haven't you?
Well, it's a title next week.
I like that.
Yeah, that's that's next.
All right.
Can I take you back to the
penalties then, okay?
So this is where the programme notes start to come into their own, Emi, all right?
Was you aware, by the way, before the penalty shootout started that you were going to kind of
Just do a little bit of theatrics.
Just try and get in the head of the French players a little bit.
Yeah, obviously I spoke with the psychologist about it because when you're controlling the game,
you concede three goals is like well at
I didn't really have a good game there.
Three goals conceded in five shots.
made a good save at the end, but that was it really.
When I go into a shootout, it's like I bring my boy into the playground.
You know, he's crying in the car.
Oh, Santi playground.
And actually, I feel like I dominate that area.
I can lose, win, or I can save one or not.
If you watch me, I went straight into the goal.
Even I had a shootout as well the other day and I went into the goal like, this is my zone, I need to control it, you know.
And then obviously I like to watch goalie.
I watch a lot of football.
I watch football every day.
And then I seen Lloris so many years in the Premier League.
I know how...
what he brings to the table.
He's a really good goalie, but
In that time, it's like it's me against him.
It's not me against Mpappe.
You know, people say, no, you in the head.
I'm in my head.
It's me against Lloris.
Is Messi against Mbappe or is, I don't know, Otamendi against Konati?
And I knew that fact at that moment.
Maybe he got more experience than me.
Maybe he played more games.
But I fall in that moment, I'm way better than you.
She's in that different game, which is shootout.
So that's when I come.
If I beat Lloris...
I got a big chance to win the World Cup.
It's like...
when it goes to penalties, it's almost like, right, it's Emi's time now.
It's a different game.
It's my house now.
This is it.
And that's how it goes down, isn't it?
Yeah, it is.
All right then, the first penalty.
Mbappe.
Top hand, nearly.
Nearly.
Were you disappointed with the first penalty?
Yeah, can we talk about timing in the goalkeeping?
Timing, get it at night, obviously...
Messi spoke about it and he does two, three steps and goes straight into the ball.
So I was...
By the time he's shooting, I'm still skipping.
Maybe she's gone a little bit earlier.
And then because I concede already too, I knew he was going right.
I knew, I definitely knew he was going right.
But then I thought, why did I not go a little bit early?
And then I went low rather than high, mid-high.
And I knew that he likes mid-high.
Shit, you know, I got it wrong, got it all wrong.
got it all wrong because for me that's a comfortable safe.
So, but at the end,
I didn't think, oh, it's not my day.
I can't say one.
I just went, if I say two...
It's coming, it's coming.
One's going to come in a minute.
When you were watching this Cuts on Holiday, you were at this point just a bag of nerves.
You probably should have said that.
He would have said that.
That's why I said it, because I know that's what he would have said.
Yeah, it's difficult because you're so far away and all you want to do is for him to win.
It's like...
You can't scream at the telly and say, you should have saved that, all right?
What are you doing?
Yeah.
No, not quite.
I'm just like desperate for him to win.
Okay, so then Messi takes the next penalty.
Excuse my language, it's a piss take of a penalty.
It is a piss take of a penalty, right?
I talk about then how Lloris do, you know, how he behaves.
I said, if you stop, you're going to score.
Because I remember Jorginho against him in the Premier League.
I think Vardy stopped as well against him.
He went way too early.
So I said, Leo, just stop and go.
He will move.
He moves to his left.
He rolls it not far off the centre of it.
In a World Cup final.
He won't stay in the middle.
Lloris will never stay in the middle.
So it's kind of like when I talk to my teammates in the national team, they listen as well.
i said go to the middle go in the middle go one at least one in the middle
So we scored two out of five because I was through the middle.
And then Kingsley Coman steps up.
Big save, comfortable save.
When you dive in that way, and it almost hits you in the chest, doesn't it?
It does hit you in the chest, yeah.
I missed it are you you just know you're saving it though don't you because you've already you're so you almost drive past it don't you
yeah but you know i i watched penalties the day before and i watched griezmann
jerut empape baran and afimwani
So then Griezmann wasn't on the pitch.
Giroud wasn't on the pitch.
Dembele wasn't on the pitch, I looked.
Baran wasn't on the pitch.
So for the in-comer, I said, I don't know where he's going.
So that's when it comes, you know, that intuition that I always believe that I back myself up.
So it's about timing.
And that's when I got a really, really, I'll say I jumped more than I should have.
It's more just, you know, I was probably so nervous.
Not so nervous, but so tense that I missed the ball and it hit my chest.
And that feeling, the way I was jumping, if he goes, yeah, that's me, that's me, I got it right, you know.
I didn't because I was so frustrated for before for not saving them puppies.
for that's more like me, you know?
Yeah.
That I find interesting.
You know where he says about that tense feeling, that nerve, it's not nerve feeling.
It's like, it's so much energy.
isn't it it's so well it's hard to describe that you almost can't feel your fingers
What, adrenaline?
Crazy.
Concentration or I don't know what that is, but it's just...
You know goalies having cramps.
How can a goalie have a cramp?
It's because you're so tense, you're so nervous that your muscle contracts, isn't it?
Yeah, that's right.
It was a comfortable save in the end.
I want to talk about the Cermény penalty though.
So third penalty for France, he drags it wide.
But this is where, and we're going to talk about shithousery in a minute if that's okay.
But this is where you came into your own a little bit.
I was buzzing off it.
I think it's a fair play if you can do it.
do it all day long you throw the ball away a little bit
And the bit that I really like about this and we talked about it a minute ago is
Um, the camera sort of pans to Tiumeni's face and he,
And he's trying to act all cool.
Like, I'm not fazed by this.
This ain't even a thing, all right?
And he has this little...
double nervous grin honestly it's so double nervous it's ridiculous right
And I'm thinking, oh, mate, I don't like the look of that.
Then the camera pans to Didier Deschamps on the sidelines.
and he's fuming it yeah he's like effing and jeffing and cussing and all that kind of stuff
And it comes back to Tumeni.
He steps up to take the penalty and it's inevitable.
Isn't it?
It is inevitable what he's going to do.
You know, I'll come to you because.
You know he's going to drag it, don't you?
Yeah, and it is one of them.
You can see it.
You can see it on his face.
You're like, oh, he's not quite sure, this boy.
And then that's when you know you've got one over straight away.
It's like, I've got him.
Like, I've got him.
But I knew it was the time because I'm never doing the first pen or the second one.
It's when I got a big chance that we can win it.
So I saved, I nearly got in pappers against the side.
I got a second one.
So I'm thinking when I
When I look at the young lad coming, it's like, if he missed that pen...
they might be losing this World Cup.
So I thought, that's when, what am I doing?
I said, he needs to go and get it further up.
You know, he needs it further up.
I need to do something, you know.
That's personality, isn't it?
And the ref was like... Pure personality and presence.
The ref didn't know what to do, you know, I felt like, no.
I just keep walking, you know, I just keep walking.
You threw it just the right.
Yeah, perfect.
Because it's hard, you know, when you walk.
yards to take the penalty, how many yards is, I don't know, but in a World Cup final.
You can practice 150 penalties in training and you can put in the top corner.
Top bins are easy.
And then when you go into a World Cup final behind all Argentinian fans,
They were singing, which that means he will eat you up.
I'm saying he's going to be feeling something at all.
I know he played for Real Madrid.
He'd be feeling something.
I can see it in his face.
But then you need to have that luck that you save it or not because otherwise you look like a twat.
Yeah.
So, and then he, I knew it was going to cross his body shape.
Kicking glue.
You know, you've been a goalie, you can see more or less.
you can't really guess by his body shape he can't go he cannot be his foot he was like he's so close
off it's the only place he can go and I thought if he was going in I would definitely save it I feel like something
You know when you...
You know, when you don't touch it, but you feel like the air or something in your hands.
I touch it.
Yeah, that's why I started dancing because I thought, yeah, I got him.
So that's what I want to talk about.
I've got here the horrible shoulder dance.
I swear my mum's like, I've never, ever done it.
I can't even move my shoulders nowadays.
I don't know how I've done it.
I've never practiced it.
It's so good.
That just came up in that moment.
Do you know how many kids are doing that now?
Oh, I know.
A friend of ours, we're going to do a podcast with him, and he said,
our little lad at the weekend.
Doing the whole thing.
Horrible, it was so horrible.
We went to Dubai with my wife and my kids and said, and these young lads, you know, on the beach,
Look what you've done.
I said, what can I do?
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
Another thing I really liked as well then is when Paredes scored his penalty and you kind of sprinted to him, he sprinted to you.
And that unity of you two, it's like...
that was your 18-yard box.
You know what I mean?
It was like it was... That whole area was just Argentine.
And...
I think the French would have even seen that happening, that little celebration and gone,
we don't belong here.
Like they sent ours.
It was inevitable at that point, wasn't it?
it becomes a habit you know because they're so good at penalties you know because
Hugo Paredes, oh my God, he can strike Messi, Dybala.
You got Montiel, never miss a pin, outpaning his career.
McAllister.
six he was a six taker he got so many takers i thought mate with the takers i got
Di Maria.
Yeah.
If I say one or two, that's it.
And they know that I can save it.
I've done it every time.
So I thought, you know, it's a...
That unity, like you said, once we got to penalties, we win.
You can win or lose.
It doesn't mean we're going to win every time.
I always say the big ones we already done it.
And when Gonzalo Montiel puts that penalty in,
The celebration is incredible, but what's it like for him now?
Because I can only kind of imagine in England, right, if...
I don't know who it is.
Somebody, John Stones runs up and scores that winning penalty for England, right?
He's just done that for Argentina.
What is he like at home?
Is he a hero?
Is...
Is the whole team a hero or is there something reserved specially for him?
You know when you're a young lad, you've got memories, isn't it?
So every child in Argentina, we remember Montiel.
like Agüero, you know, and that moment, you know, when you're young, you just, you've got memories, so...
I think whatever happens in Montiel's career, he will be well known back home forever, you know.
Forever, forever a legend.
I loved it when it finished because it was
No one will remember Paredes penalty in 10 years.
No chance.
Montiel's.
Maybe Messi, Maizé and Montillo, even though he played 10 minutes in the World Cup, in the final.
really yeah there was two there was two focal points of the celebration wasn't there there was you and there was there was messy
And then half the team kind of split and it was just, it was absolute chaos, wasn't it?
There's no fans more
passionate than Argentina.
No, no.
They're like incredible, aren't they?
I always say to you, come to Argentina to watch me play.
It's just...
I went to Miami tonight just before you went to the World Cup.
Yeah.
before probably the last camp that you went to.
In Argentina they choose 60,000 pounds singing and
jumping and then you just go back placing your tummy and then
The adrenaline, you know, I never felt pressure before, ever.
Obviously, when you're young, yes, but when I was older, I never thought coming into a game
But when I went into the first game of the World Cup.
Saudi Arabia game.
And I walk onto the pitch with all the fans screaming in that scenario.
I felt like a heat inside my body that I'd never felt before, ever.
And I felt it in the World Cup final going into the warm up.
Then in the game, I was good.
But running into my zone, the area, the box with the fans,
It was like, oh my God, I feel like something I never felt before.
Even nowadays, playing big games, I never...
I'm not feeling that.
What was it?
Nerves?
Anxiety?
Energy?
Not as...
You know when you're nervous in a game, you want to go to the toilet maybe, or maybe you go buy flights, you know that?
feeling in this one which is a heat inside your body like burning inside weird
that's honestly I knew I was looking forward to it we were looking forward to it but how good was that
The best.
Emi, you're the man.
Kurt, you're not bad either.
It's been The False Cast.
I hope you enjoyed it.
We'll see you soon.