The winner of the Yashin Trophy, elected by hundred donades representing the top hundred nations in the FIFA rankings. Lautaro Dionay is yours.
El ganador es Emiliano Martínez.
Emiliano  you again, you. Few first words, please.
Bueno, ante todo, como dijo el toro, muchas gracias a todos.
Es un honor volver a estar acá.
Obviamente siempre me ha agradecido, recién mismo el lautaro, meter el gol en la final.
Mis compañeros de la selección, Alaston Villa, hoy tengo el placer de estar con los dos  entrenadores arquero mío que me ven todos los días,
sabe lo exigente que soy, a seguir mejorando.
Vengo siempre de un lugar chico y siempre lo recuerdo y eso es lo que me motiva siempre a.
A seguir queriendo crecer, a seguir obsesionado con mejorar, conseguir cosas grupales que para mí es lo individual. Siempre viene después de lo grupal,
así que nada, agradecidos a todos, siempre y gracias. Bueno, a todo lo que metió gol en la final.
Congratulations, Emiliano.
What an amazing year you've had.
Let's watch together how you became the Impassable.
The best goalkeeper award at a major tournament for Emiliano Martinez.
Emiliano  You win this trophy back to back.
This is first time in history.  This is huge for you.
Yeah, to be first.
He's huge for me.
You know, I always dream I play one game for the national team.
You know, and you know, coming from such a young lad to England,
you know, trying to walk my way through, succeed Austin Villa and the national team, you know,
winning ones for me was an honor, you know, back to back is something that I never expected to be fair.
I'm just proud to be here today and all thanks to my family and my friends.
you're a very special person.
I think we all know that now.
You're kind of a showman.
You know, you like to provoke your opponents.
You like to unsettle them.
We never know what your next move will be.
Is that you like your special touch?
No, it's not my special touch.
You know, sometimes when you're on the pitch, you behave the way you want to win the game.
You know, off the pitch, I'm a dad.
You know I'm a pro man, you know, I'm a husband, I'm a brother.  I'm a son.
On the pitch, I just want to do everything I can to help my national team and my club, which is Aston Villa.
You know, we're doing something amazing in the club.
We're moving forward, you know. We won back-to-back trophies with the national team, and that's all I care, to be fair.
Good.
But sometimes it can be seen as too much, right?
Well, that's the way you see it, you know, for Argentinian people now.
Perfect. Perfect answer.
You even have to apologize, even how to apologize.
But you are the best keeper, goalkeeper in the world right now.
You know, being elected back to back champion, winning the Copa America,
I mean, you're the best.
Now, to be fair, I don't see myself as the best.
You know, there's so many good goalies I see today that I see week in, week out.
Like I said, I only care about group titles, you know, with the national team, we Aston Villa, that's sort of focus on myself mostly.
My Gobley coach is now more than me.
The work I put every day.
We have Ian Martin.
So for me to improve myself, that's like a.
Lautaro,We want to know how is Emiliano out of the pitch or in the locker room? You see him every day.
Bueno, Emiliano.
Para nosotros es una persona especial porque es ganador primera cosa
y eso es importante dentro de un de un equipo.
Después.  Ayuda a los más jóvenes,
ayuda a los chicos que vienen a entrenar con nosotros en la selección
después puedo hablar solo palabras bonitas hacia él porque.
es una gran persona.
Como dije antes, quizá todo lo que hace, lo hace porque él quiere ganar  y no va más allá de eso.
Great example for young goalkeepers.
Lautaro, if you had to take 10 penalty shots against Emiliano,
the specialist of course, how many do you think you would score?
No mientas.
No sé, muy difícil.
Five, ten?
Un poco más.
Pero es muy difícil, es muy difícil porque primero es grande y segundo espera hasta lo último. Mira mucho.
¿Y vos, Didier, vos amitaría conmigo?
how many would you actually score Didier?
Maybe 9,10.
He's still in good shape.
Thank you very much.
Ladies and gentlemen, shall be Emiliano Martinez.