mainly outfield, but with such an in-depth knowledge of the biomechanics or biomechanical movement
That he can help you a lot couldn't he probably helped you a lot with India within your physio and your rehab like and
If you've got that in-depth knowledge of biomechanics and how goalkeepers move, huge.
Right then, mate.
So you've made the save.
Full-time whistle's gone.
Penalty shootout, okay?
This is... We were watching it, wasn't we?
And we knew what was gonna happen.
It was inevitable.
and this is no slight on Hugo Lloris, but
when you put Hugo Lloris in goal and then you put you in goal, the size difference is just phenomenal.
so sort of daunting and you just failed the goal.
I don't think it's size though, is it?
What do you think it is?
I think it's personality.
Aura.
I think it's, again, it's,
It boils down to confidence to the point of arrogance.
You see the look on the face and the way you hold yourself.
Small goalies can strip well, yeah?
Like you've got some small goalies that you think are big on the pitch when they're quite small.
And some goalies that are big and look small.
The big ones that look small in the goal and come off the pitch and go, yeah, actually quite big.
Yeah, it's true, yeah.
And it's like, it's what you bring in terms of your personality.
Yeah.
it's like the um we went to man united away and the ronaldo thing remember it yeah yeah
And who was it who missed the penalty?
Bruno.
And we spoke about it before, didn't we?
What, what, what?
What little details can you bring into your game that's going to make you this person?
And it has to be that.
personality.
You've got to bring an aura, a personality, a real like.
I'm not going to get beat.
Whereas it's not down to size.
It's your presence.
We said that when we were watching the game.
We actually said that
And he's making the goal look small.
Yeah.
And like you were saying earlier on, cuts about...
how you conduct yourself, you know, shoulders back.
It's that aura, isn't it?
Making yourself big.
Bigger.
You know, he'd look in his eyes and go, he's saving it.
Yeah.
It's not because he's big.
It's just like...
Yeah.
Even I suppose it's a lanky after getting to you.
Why do you put it so high?
I've never seen you put in that high.
So may
i don't know where to go you you made it i have to go really yeah
I actually asked Solanki, I said, it's a great pen, but why do you go so high?
We watch penalties, so you never go that high.
I said, mate, I have to change something.
I have to go there.
Because he knows you'll save it otherwise.
Yeah, that's fascinating.
You know, you can get there to the side.
I know you can get to the side, so I have to put a right in the corner.
This is what this, that, that I will only back myself up a little bit and say, when I say about size, right?
Some of the penalties,
you are nearly touching the post.
By the time you finish a sable, when you get your hand on the ball,
you're nearly on the post.
That's not size, is it?
It's got to be size.
No.
What is it?
It's...
speed power push and power you don't have to yeah i think i believe that is power and timing yeah
Timing.
I'm all over this.
I'm not saying, I always say if you get the timing right,
I'll reach a post just the timing if you're going to save a penalty you don't
go to the ball, dear.
To be fair, anyone can save a penalty.
Go through the ball, go past the ball, his speed and his power, how quick he can go from here to there.
Right?
And it has to be like, boom.
So it's timing and speed and power.
Speed equals distance divided by... How quickly you can transfer your body weight, isn't it?
how quickly you can get onto your leading leg.
I've got to ask you, Emi,
Some of the viewers might think this is a strange question, but we've had professor Steve Peters on psychologists on
And they talk about the gold medal syndrome.
Now, World Cup's the biggest prize you can win.
Did you have a moment where you had that...
gold medal syndrome where you almost had a low after or not.
No.
Not just high.
Always high, yeah.
But...
After the shoot, after the World Cup, when I was home, I said,
i reached my dream i can't go any higher because the feeling i had after that work up is like
Even if I win the next one, I already know what I felt.
So now what's next?
When you win the Golden Glove in the Copa America,
You win the Super Cup, you win the Golden Glove and the World Cup.
It's like, what else can I win?
Like, if you win the best on Yashin, which I won, it's just individual, you know.
I wanted the World Cup since I was five years old.
My boy is obsessed with the World Cup.
That's why I wanted to win.
But now that's when the psychology comes.
What's next?
How can I be motivated when I already reached my dreams?
It kind of answers my question.
Like I said, maybe I positioned it incorrectly and low, but...
I always find a way.
I want to get Aston Villa in the Champions League.
I was upset with it.
I was like, I need to get this club because he...
I won the World Cup after 38 years in Argentina, won the Copa America after 30 years,
We never beat Brazil in the Maracanã.
The first game that they lost in qualifiers in history was against us.
in December, so I always find leader target like
huge target because let's say you play for Man United you qualify you make top four it's
You know, it's a big season.
Even if he's starting on with Chelsea, it's more or less anyone can do it or, you know, it's a big club.
Aston Villa 42 years I said what if
I can do it.
What if we're done?
It's something like...
it's hard to do special it's it's that's me it's challenging myself
That's the equivalent of Man City winning the league, isn't it?
Really, let's be honest.
Villa getting in the Champions League is...
It's huge.
It's absolutely monumental.
And for me, and I say that to my mum, I say that to my agents,
It means more staying in a club like Villa
and deliver what I was dreaming.
It's like winning a title with Argentina.
So what next?
You've got to win the Champions League then because you've ticked everything else off, haven't you?
Well, it's a title next week.
I like that.
Yeah, that's that's next.
All right.
Can I take you back to the
penalties then, okay?
So this is where the programme notes start to come into their own, Emi, all right?
Was you aware, by the way, before the penalty shootout started that you were going to kind of
Just do a little bit of theatrics.
Just try and get in the head of the French players a little bit.
Yeah, obviously I spoke with the psychologist about it because when you're controlling the game,
you concede three goals is like well at
I didn't really have a good game there.
Three goals conceded in five shots.
made a good save at the end, but that was it really.
When I go into a shootout, it's like I bring my boy into the playground.
You know, he's crying in the car.
Oh, Santi playground.
And actually, I feel like I dominate that area.
I can lose, win, or I can save one or not.
If you watch me, I went straight into the goal.
Even I had a shootout as well the other day and I went into the goal like, this is my zone, I need to control it, you know.
And then obviously I like to watch goalie.
I watch a lot of football.
I watch football every day.
And then I seen Lloris so many years in the Premier League.
I know how...
what he brings to the table.
He's a really good goalie, but
In that time, it's like it's me against him.
It's not me against Mpappe.
You know, people say, no, you in the head.
I'm in my head.
It's me against Lloris.
Is Messi against Mbappe or is, I don't know, Otamendi against Konati?
And I knew that fact at that moment.
Maybe he got more experience than me.
Maybe he played more games.
But I fall in that moment, I'm way better than you.
She's in that different game, which is shootout.
So that's when I come.
If I beat Lloris...
I got a big chance to win the World Cup.
It's like...
when it goes to penalties, it's almost like, right, it's Emi's time now.
It's a different game.
It's my house now.
This is it.
And that's how it goes down, isn't it?
Yeah, it is.
All right then, the first penalty.
Mbappe.
Top hand, nearly.
Nearly.
Were you disappointed with the first penalty?
Yeah, can we talk about timing in the goalkeeping?
Timing, get it at night, obviously...
Messi spoke about it and he does two, three steps and goes straight into the ball.
So I was...
By the time he's shooting, I'm still skipping.
Maybe she's gone a little bit earlier.
And then because I concede already too, I knew he was going right.
I knew, I definitely knew he was going right.
But then I thought, why did I not go a little bit early?
And then I went low rather than high, mid-high.
And I knew that he likes mid-high.
Shit, you know, I got it wrong, got it all wrong.
got it all wrong because for me that's a comfortable safe.
So, but at the end,
I didn't think, oh, it's not my day.
I can't say one.
I just went, if I say two...
It's coming, it's coming.
One's going to come in a minute.
When you were watching this Cuts on Holiday, you were at this point just a bag of nerves.
You probably should have said that.
He would have said that.
That's why I said it, because I know that's what he would have said.
Yeah, it's difficult because you're so far away and all you want to do is for him to win.
It's like...
You can't scream at the telly and say, you should have saved that, all right?
What are you doing?
Yeah.
No, not quite.
I'm just like desperate for him to win.
Okay, so then Messi takes the next penalty.
Excuse my language, it's a piss take of a penalty.
It is a piss take of a penalty, right?
I talk about then how Lloris do, you know, how he behaves.
I said, if you stop, you're going to score.
Because I remember Jorginho against him in the Premier League.
I think Vardy stopped as well against him.
He went way too early.
So I said, Leo, just stop and go.
He will move.
He moves to his left.
He rolls it not far off the centre of it.
In a World Cup final.
He won't stay in the middle.
Lloris will never stay in the middle.
So it's kind of like when I talk to my teammates in the national team, they listen as well.
i said go to the middle go in the middle go one at least one in the middle
So we scored two out of five because I was through the middle.
And then Kingsley Coman steps up.
Big save, comfortable save.
When you dive in that way, and it almost hits you in the chest, doesn't it?
It does hit you in the chest, yeah.
I missed it are you you just know you're saving it though don't you because you've already you're so you almost drive past it don't you
yeah but you know i i watched penalties the day before and i watched griezmann
jerut empape baran and afimwani
So then Griezmann wasn't on the pitch.
Giroud wasn't on the pitch.
Dembele wasn't on the pitch, I looked.
Baran wasn't on the pitch.
So for the in-comer, I said, I don't know where he's going.
So that's when it comes, you know, that intuition that I always believe that I back myself up.
So it's about timing.
And that's when I got a really, really, I'll say I jumped more than I should have.
It's more just, you know, I was probably so nervous.
Not so nervous, but so tense that I missed the ball and it hit my chest.
And that feeling, the way I was jumping, if he goes, yeah, that's me, that's me, I got it right, you know.
I didn't because I was so frustrated for before for not saving them puppies.
for that's more like me, you know?
Yeah.
That I find interesting.
You know where he says about that tense feeling, that nerve, it's not nerve feeling.
It's like, it's so much energy.
isn't it it's so well it's hard to describe that you almost can't feel your fingers
What, adrenaline?
Crazy.
Concentration or I don't know what that is, but it's just...
You know goalies having cramps.
How can a goalie have a cramp?
It's because you're so tense, you're so nervous that your muscle contracts, isn't it?
Yeah, that's right.
It was a comfortable save in the end.
I want to talk about the Cermény penalty though.
So third penalty for France, he drags it wide.
But this is where, and we're going to talk about shithousery in a minute if that's okay.
But this is where you came into your own a little bit.
I was buzzing off it.
I think it's a fair play if you can do it.
do it all day long you throw the ball away a little bit
And the bit that I really like about this and we talked about it a minute ago is
Um, the camera sort of pans to Tiumeni's face and he,
And he's trying to act all cool.
Like, I'm not fazed by this.
This ain't even a thing, all right?
And he has this little...
double nervous grin honestly it's so double nervous it's ridiculous right
And I'm thinking, oh, mate, I don't like the look of that.
Then the camera pans to Didier Deschamps on the sidelines.
and he's fuming it yeah he's like effing and jeffing and cussing and all that kind of stuff
And it comes back to Tumeni.
He steps up to take the penalty and it's inevitable.
Isn't it?
It is inevitable what he's going to do.
You know, I'll come to you because.
You know he's going to drag it, don't you?
Yeah, and it is one of them.
You can see it.
You can see it on his face.
You're like, oh, he's not quite sure, this boy.
And then that's when you know you've got one over straight away.
It's like, I've got him.
Like, I've got him.
But I knew it was the time because I'm never doing the first pen or the second one.
It's when I got a big chance that we can win it.
So I saved, I nearly got in pappers against the side.
I got a second one.
So I'm thinking when I
When I look at the young lad coming, it's like, if he missed that pen...
they might be losing this World Cup.
So I thought, that's when, what am I doing?
I said, he needs to go and get it further up.
You know, he needs it further up.
I need to do something, you know.
That's personality, isn't it?
And the ref was like... Pure personality and presence.
The ref didn't know what to do, you know, I felt like, no.
I just keep walking, you know, I just keep walking.
You threw it just the right.
Yeah, perfect.
Because it's hard, you know, when you walk.
yards to take the penalty, how many yards is, I don't know, but in a World Cup final.
You can practice 150 penalties in training and you can put in the top corner.
Top bins are easy.
And then when you go into a World Cup final behind all Argentinian fans,
They were singing, which that means he will eat you up.
I'm saying he's going to be feeling something at all.
I know he played for Real Madrid.
He'd be feeling something.
I can see it in his face.
But then you need to have that luck that you save it or not because otherwise you look like a twat.
Yeah.
So, and then he, I knew it was going to cross his body shape.
Kicking glue.
You know, you've been a goalie, you can see more or less.
you can't really guess by his body shape he can't go he cannot be his foot he was like he's so close
off it's the only place he can go and I thought if he was going in I would definitely save it I feel like something
You know when you...
You know, when you don't touch it, but you feel like the air or something in your hands.
I touch it.
Yeah, that's why I started dancing because I thought, yeah, I got him.
So that's what I want to talk about.
I've got here the horrible shoulder dance.
I swear my mum's like, I've never, ever done it.
I can't even move my shoulders nowadays.
I don't know how I've done it.
I've never practiced it.
It's so good.
That just came up in that moment.
Do you know how many kids are doing that now?
Oh, I know.
A friend of ours, we're going to do a podcast with him, and he said,
our little lad at the weekend.
Doing the whole thing.
Horrible, it was so horrible.
We went to Dubai with my wife and my kids and said, and these young lads, you know, on the beach,
Look what you've done.
I said, what can I do?
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
Another thing I really liked as well then is when Paredes scored his penalty and you kind of sprinted to him, he sprinted to you.
And that unity of you two, it's like...
that was your 18-yard box.
You know what I mean?
It was like it was... That whole area was just Argentine.
And...
I think the French would have even seen that happening, that little celebration and gone,
we don't belong here.
Like they sent ours.
It was inevitable at that point, wasn't it?
it becomes a habit you know because they're so good at penalties you know because
Hugo Paredes, oh my God, he can strike Messi, Dybala.
You got Montiel, never miss a pin, outpaning his career.
McAllister.
six he was a six taker he got so many takers i thought mate with the takers i got
Di Maria.
Yeah.
If I say one or two, that's it.
And they know that I can save it.
I've done it every time.
So I thought, you know, it's a...
That unity, like you said, once we got to penalties, we win.
You can win or lose.
It doesn't mean we're going to win every time.
I always say the big ones we already done it.
And when Gonzalo Montiel puts that penalty in,
The celebration is incredible, but what's it like for him now?
Because I can only kind of imagine in England, right, if...
I don't know who it is.
Somebody, John Stones runs up and scores that winning penalty for England, right?
He's just done that for Argentina.
What is he like at home?
Is he a hero?
Is...
Is the whole team a hero or is there something reserved specially for him?
You know when you're a young lad, you've got memories, isn't it?
So every child in Argentina, we remember Montiel.
like Agüero, you know, and that moment, you know, when you're young, you just, you've got memories, so...
I think whatever happens in Montiel's career, he will be well known back home forever, you know.
Forever, forever a legend.
I loved it when it finished because it was
No one will remember Paredes penalty in 10 years.
No chance.
Montiel's.
Maybe Messi, Maizé and Montillo, even though he played 10 minutes in the World Cup, in the final.
really yeah there was two there was two focal points of the celebration wasn't there there was you and there was there was messy
And then half the team kind of split and it was just, it was absolute chaos, wasn't it?
There's no fans more
passionate than Argentina.
No, no.
They're like incredible, aren't they?
I always say to you, come to Argentina to watch me play.
It's just...
I went to Miami tonight just before you went to the World Cup.
Yeah.
before probably the last camp that you went to.
In Argentina they choose 60,000 pounds singing and
jumping and then you just go back placing your tummy and then
The adrenaline, you know, I never felt pressure before, ever.
Obviously, when you're young, yes, but when I was older, I never thought coming into a game
But when I went into the first game of the World Cup.
Saudi Arabia game.
And I walk onto the pitch with all the fans screaming in that scenario.
I felt like a heat inside my body that I'd never felt before, ever.
And I felt it in the World Cup final going into the warm up.
Then in the game, I was good.
But running into my zone, the area, the box with the fans,
It was like, oh my God, I feel like something I never felt before.
Even nowadays, playing big games, I never...
I'm not feeling that.
What was it?
Nerves?
Anxiety?
Energy?
Not as...
You know when you're nervous in a game, you want to go to the toilet maybe, or maybe you go buy flights, you know that?
feeling in this one which is a heat inside your body like burning inside weird
that's honestly I knew I was looking forward to it we were looking forward to it but how good was that
The best.
Emi, you're the man.
Kurt, you're not bad either.
It's been The False Cast.
I hope you enjoyed it.
We'll see you soon.